<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>if we hung out - 333vinyl</title><description>The name of this site is 333vinyl. That's what it's about.</description><link>http://333vinyl.us/</link><generator>Ghost 0.5</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 21:47:26 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://333vinyl.us/tag/if-we-hung-out/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>If We Hung Out [002]</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the second edition of &lt;a href="http://333vinyl.us/authors/mason-lynaugh.html"&gt;Mason Lynaugh's&lt;/a&gt; If We Hung Out. This edition features Travi$ Scott, Andrea, and Jimmy Johnson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://333vinyl.us/content/images/2014/11/travi.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/travisscott-2/04-drugs-you-should-try-it"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Travi$ Scott - "Drugs You Should Try It"&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Around two weeks ago, Travi$ Scott released a surprise mixtape. Not only was it a surprise in terms of release–he pulled a Beyonce–but it was also surprisingly put together. Travis Scott, an XXL freshman from 2013, has a lot of enemies for good reasons. He first made ripples throughout the blogosphere when he released &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Vld3uWewvyI"&gt;"Lights"&lt;/a&gt;, and, clearly rife with talent, he continued to generate buzz until he signed a 360 deal as a producer for &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KC-1AaTonTs"&gt;G.O.O.D. Music&lt;/a&gt; and a rapper for &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2uQfbc3NLz8"&gt;Grand Hustle&lt;/a&gt;. However, his entire career has been marred with scandal. He has been attacked for ragging on T.I. and Jay-Z, two of his collaborators, stealing beats, album artwork, and aggravating fans by heedlessly making and subsequently missing release dates. His debut mixtape "Owl Pharaoh", was a testament to his nature. It was messy, uneven, and poorly handled, but it provided the listener with glimpses into his mind and his obvious talent behind the mic and the boards. “Drugs You Should Try It” is haunting and magnificent. The auto-tuned wailing adds a shocking amount of humanity to a poignant sample, and Scott’s rapping has made dramatic improvement. The entire mixtape is worth a listen, especially these  &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dY5F5EsQwqE"&gt;two&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qFbrRXdruv4"&gt;songs&lt;/a&gt;. You’ll find an incredible level of depth to the production, especially in the latter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://333vinyl.us/content/images/2014/11/andrea.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4fhwCvafjYA"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Andrea - "Your Morning"&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Anyone who knows me knows that this is one of my all time favorite songs. By a French producer named Andrea (whether that is pronounced anh-drey-ah or ann-dree-ah is beyond me), who is actually not a female, despite the name. To me, it is the perfect morning song (apt title), and the ideal song for a sunny day in a green field. I use it as an alarm on my iPhone because it makes waking up enjoyable, and I have so much nostalgia attached to it that on rough days it can bring up some emotions, ya feel? Sonically, it reminds me of water flowing through a creek. I’m sitting there adjacent two a pair of stones engulfed in moss, and smiling with a childhood friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://333vinyl.us/content/images/2014/11/jimyjohn.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xPgcSFO6qOg"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jimmy Johnson - "Northside"&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: For almost a year the Toronto-based rapper Jimmy Johnson and Austin, Texas producer Eric Dingus have been making relatively silent moves above the border. Affiliated with the label "Prime", Johnson and Dingus have been inching into the inner circle of Drake’s imprint OVO, and with the title of Drake’s 4th studio effort inspired by Jimmy Johnson, popularizer of the term “The 6”, it seems they have cemented their place. Jimmy Johnson is a fairly middle of the line rapper, but when he combines his vocals with auto-tune and a signature Dingus beat, he does what many auto-tune proficinatos does and becomes more of an instrument than an MC. “Northside” is his best effort yet, with a gritty beat and an infectious chorus, while his debut mixtape some has &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=j-4uWvz3bJk"&gt;gems&lt;/a&gt; as well (the mixtape is fairly good and is definitely worth a few listens). Dingus as well, is someone to watch. I give him until Drake’s next album (which I assume will include his production) to blow up even more than he already has. After &lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/octobersveryown/octobers-very-own-presents-haw-eric-dingus-mixtape"&gt;performing&lt;/a&gt; at OVO’s Houston Appreciation Weekend, and being featured on the OVO blog &lt;a href="http://octobersveryown.blogspot.com/2013/11/drake-worst-behavior-eric-dingus-remix.html"&gt;multiple times&lt;/a&gt;, his remixes are getting serious traffic. His label, Dream Sequence Records, is working on assembling a roster and already has reached some &lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/dream-sequence-records/dowrong-shooters-prod-eric"&gt;talent&lt;/a&gt;. Jimmy Johnson and Eric Dingus should definitely be on your radar.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://333vinyl.us/if-we-hung-out-002/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">373b181c-e2eb-45b9-b749-87e48f0e6088</guid><category>articles</category><category>if we hung out</category><dc:creator>Mason Lynaugh</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>If We Hung Out [001]</title><description>&lt;p&gt;My name is Mason Lynaugh and I will occasionally be contributing to 333vinyl. My musical tastes include Ben’s, but are more concerned with the most recent developments in hip hop - whether it be drill, coastal, trap, or slip-hop - so I will focus mainly on what has been blaring through my speakers on its path to being overplayed. I’m planning on doing periodical entries under the terrible title “if we hung out” because “songs I would make you listen to if we hung out” was a bit worse, and the people who do hang out with me would attest to its accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="more"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://333vinyl.us/content/images/2014/11/kanye.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r4NTDoPQ4mU"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kanye West - All Day (Remake)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: A triumphant victory for the lovely people over at KTT (or &lt;a href="http://333vinyl.us/ktt.jpg"&gt;KanyeToThe&lt;/a&gt;, a forum I endearingly refer to as the 4chan of hip hop) came the day in which someone announced they had a leak of the impending single from Kanye’s untitled seventh solo album. Ironically, this “leak” with the sound quality of something recorded on a graphing calculator triggered an infuriated Kanye to retreat back to Mexico and re-record for an album already rumored to be complete. Nonetheless, since I am part of that seeming minority that doesn’t mind Kanye’s rants, debauchery, or wife, and enjoys his music, I love this remake. Despite being full of mumbling, filler freestyle, unfinished lines, and of shoebox audio quality, it still bumps in the whip, dog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://333vinyl.us/content/images/2014/11/ilm.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HRQyg8RHvIQ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I LOVE MAKONNEN - I Don’t Sell Molly No More&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: ILM has recently received an unprecedented amount of attention for a singer who wails over beats churned out by ATL’s trap oligarchy while &lt;a href="http://www.foxylounge.com/IMG/jpg/i_love_makonnen_tumblr_mcxyf4addm1qlcgcbo1_500-2.jpg"&gt;undeniably resembling a plush toy in appearance&lt;/a&gt;. This is result of current king of rap Drake remixing his fantastic song &lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/octobersveryown/makonnen-ft-drake-tuesday"&gt;“Club Going Up On A Tuesday”&lt;/a&gt;.  “I Don’t Sell” is a grimy gem amongst ballads about mutual infidelity from his &lt;a href="http://www.hotnewhiphop.com/ilovemakonnen-i-love-makonnen-ep-new-mixtape.114225.html"&gt;self-titled EP&lt;/a&gt;, and is one of those songs that people “listen to as a joke” but show definite signs of enjoyment when it is played (think &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JxLS-cpgbe0"&gt;“Dolce and Gabanna”&lt;/a&gt;). I personally love ILM and look forward to his growth as an artist now that he has garnered some limelight a la &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OmHW9IzZYzU"&gt;Migos&lt;/a&gt;. No, I don’t care that you think he sounds like &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iq_d8VSM0nw"&gt;IceJJFish&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://333vinyl.us/content/images/2014/11/rustie.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_mO2VcJAkOw"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rustie - Attak (feat. Danny Brown)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: This is one of those songs that you may have already burnt out on if you’re a self-identifying “hip hop head”, into the contemporary EDM scene, or someone who lurks on Soundcloud. “Attak” marks the fourth collaboration between the two, and I see it as rivaling the incredible &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=22eSJgqxnX4"&gt;“Side B (Dope Song)"&lt;/a&gt; in quality. If you like Danny Brown, Rustie, Electronic music, and/or rap (that should be most everyone), this might tickle your pickle a little. Definitely a party starter up there with the Young Thug cut &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=34LyiriE6eo"&gt;“Old English”&lt;/a&gt; (also a must-listen).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://333vinyl.us/content/images/2014/11/mustard.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.howflyhiphop.com/2014/08/11/dj-mustard-face-down-download-mp3-lil-wayne-big-sean/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Face down (feat. Lil Wayne, Lil Boosie, Big Sean, YG)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Say what you will about DJ Mustard, I stand by my position that he has carved a ubiquitous sound and is deserving of all success. Some may get annoyed by the “aye aye aye” and the way that he uses the same sample kit across his entire discography, but those sounds have some parasitic quality that will infect its way to the top 40. “Face Down” comes from his rudimentary debut album 10 Summers, yet is anything but. It’s a classic love story - “she like her ass tooted up and her face down” with yet another verse from a Lil Wayne who is making admirable progress in &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VmddPo_c2oE"&gt;proving he’s still got it&lt;/a&gt;. However, the real standout here is Big Sean:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Oh my God, I’m in love with a porn star  
I’m in love with a foreign car, they both topless  
I done tricked off a gold Rolle wrist watch  
Man, I’m tired of dealing with these h--- but my d--- not  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://333vinyl.us/content/images/2014/11/mensa.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5jUGAVUwhRU"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Down On My Luck - Vic Mensa&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: By this point everyone knows Disclosure from &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=93ASUImTedo"&gt;“Latch”&lt;/a&gt;, but this Disclosure-produced song hasn’t gotten the love it deserves. I have trouble determining whether it’s alliance lies with EDM or rap, but those familiar with Vic Mensa know how his catalog dabbles in expansive &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZLp7M5SMBkQ"&gt;sonic&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gbcyfRztHmw"&gt;palettes&lt;/a&gt;. “Down On My Luck” is coupled with a clever Groundhog Day-inspired music video that serves as the cherry on top of one of my favorite jams for late drives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://333vinyl.us/content/images/2014/11/trae.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=D2IfOEp5iyE"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trae Tha Truth - Try Me (feat. Young Thug)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: I think Young Thug is the most interesting rapper making noise right now, and he is my second favorite rapper (behind Drake). He’s doing things that are just weird, and reaching commercial success &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5-0kZ_jeIHI"&gt;where other oddballs like Lil B couldn’t&lt;/a&gt;. His charisma and shrill, drawling flow permeate through a song until he owns it &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=etfIdtm-OC8"&gt;whether he is “featured” or not&lt;/a&gt;. Case in point, “Try Me” shows Young Thug partnering with the typically forgettable H-town hero to craft a contender for banger of the year.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://333vinyl.us/if-we-hung-out-001/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6c32bcae-6482-42ce-9515-845d6891fe8c</guid><category>articles</category><category>if we hung out</category><dc:creator>Mason Lynaugh</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2014 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>