<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Mason Lynaugh - 333vinyl</title><description>The name of this site is 333vinyl. That's what it's about.</description><link>http://333vinyl.us/</link><generator>Ghost 0.5</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 21:47:26 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://333vinyl.us/author/masonlynaugh/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>Drake - If You’re Reading This It’s Too Late</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://333vinyl.us/content/images/2015/03/drake-reading-this-too-late.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drake is the best out there right now and I’ll go to bat for that statement. His influence on the current playing field is undeniable and unmatched, and while rappers like Kendrick Lamar may possess unmatched technical prowess and have stellar releases, no one in hip hop has Drake’s stopping power. A Drake co-sign can turn nobodies into stars (ILOVEMAKONNEN, Dej Loaf) or be the catalyst for cross-over (2 Chainz, A$AP Rocky, The Weeknd). So whether Drake’s new release is a ‘surprise album’ or a mixtape release preceded by &lt;a href="http://333vinyl.us/www.kanyetothe.com/forum/index.php?topic=2637065.0"&gt;calculated hints&lt;/a&gt;, the hip hop community suffered a collective heart attack when IYRTITL dropped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any speculation that IYRTITL is merely a ruse to eschew his Cash Money ties or classification as throwaway tracks from his upcoming release does nothing but magnify how impressive the quality of this project is. Aurally, Drake has taken the unique sound crafted by 40 and 1da in past releases and made it more muddled and darker where 2013’s &lt;em&gt;Nothing Was the Same was crisp&lt;/em&gt;. Songs like "Energy" sound—as Drake described himself—"evil" and where he once sounded triumphant, he is jaded and vicious. Drake finds success through delivery rather than lyrics more so than ever in IFYRITL, and besides his usual phenomenal ability to melodize almost anything, he has more punch yet it seems almost nonchalant. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Songs like “Know Yourself” and “10 Bands” could easily hold up to any other fan-favorites and “Legend”—while no competition to “Over My Dead Body”—is arguably his next best album-opener. “Used To” is even better than its appearance on &lt;em&gt;Sorry For the Wait 2&lt;/em&gt; without Wayne’s autotune plus a biting second Drake verse, and “Preach” has an outrageously stupid yet effective hook that hasn’t left me since I first heard it. However, the album begins to lose some luster with some of the last few tracks. “You &amp;amp; 6” is a touching song, but comes off as boring and ending almost all of his rhymes with ‘mama’ doesn’t do much but irritate. Additionally, “6PM in New York” is one Drake’s weakest straight-bars songs and I prefer to end a listen with the silky “Jungle”. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If IYRTITL was meant to hold fans over until Views From the 6 then it exceeded in all regards. It can be hold its ground against Drake’s best releases and surpassed all of Drake’s other mixtapes. IYRTITL is indicative of Drake’s growth—a great example of him "rapping like the throne should be the three of y’all."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: Drake  
Album: If You’re Reading This It’s Too Late  
Score: 4.0  
Label: YMCMB  
Release: 2015/2/12  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description><link>http://333vinyl.us/drake-if-youre-reading-this-its-too-late/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">0a673bf2-7b1e-4daf-a8e1-6c484a16370f</guid><category>reviews</category><dc:creator>Mason Lynaugh</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 21:40:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Yung Lean - Unknown Memory</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://333vinyl.us/content/images/2014/11/yung_lean-unknown_memory.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Used to be a hobby now it’s all I think about // That’s what rap does&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yung Lean is undeniably interesting. He first garnered attention with &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vrQWhFysPKY"&gt;"Ginseng Strip 2002"&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=stgrSjynPKs"&gt;"Hurt"&lt;/a&gt;, and while he came off as a goofy swede adopting esoteric internet culture, he was-in the purest form-just a young hip-hop fan. He was an avid listener who, freed from any American preconceptions about rap and lucky enough to be around some incredibly musical producers, just went for it. It worked: they made a great project, established a ravenous fanbase, and garnered internet-wide attention. Lean clearly found his calling and realized he wanted to eschew any association with so-called "meme rap."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So he released &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tMgkt9jdjTU"&gt;"Kyoto"&lt;/a&gt;, a song that caught doubters off-gaurd. To many, the song still seemed ridiculous, his rapping terrible, and the video over-the-top silly, but to those who had seen "Hurt" saw the metamorphosis. Unknown Memory is the product of this change, the creation of a Yung Lean who unexpectedly became a full-fledged rap star; complete with a sold-out tour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gone are many of the nonsensical lines and perpetual non-sequiturs. Yung Lean replaces them with confidence, introspective musings, and braggadocio that–while it was seen as comedic in past work–in many cases can now be assumed true. This is what a lot of the disappointment and negative reactions stem from. Making the switch from quasi-joke rapper to post quasi-joke rapper with more serious songs puts him in limbo–should be compared with traditional rappers? Or should he be lumped with the rappers who get a handicap for being a “meme”? Yung Lean is transitioning, what some could even posture as artistic growth. Shedding mumbling for an auto-tune drawl a la Future does him favors in furthering his confidence, and complements the production fantastically. And that is what Lean is all about, he is yet another instrument to the Yung Gud or the Yung Sherman band which backs him up. In tracks like “Yoshi City” and “Ghosttown” Lean seems most formidable, and these are easily the most “Kyoto”-esque in terms of accessibility. “Ice Cold Smoke” is the most auto-tuned, but with slow skittering hats, a short time stamp, and a fantastic beat switch, it is digestible. Lean succeeds again with infectious choruses–I catch myself singing “Don’t Go” and “Blinded” at various points during the day. However, in songs like “Sandman” and “Volt” the beats are overly busy, and Lean’s raps do not mesh. The instrumental tracks also did nothing but annoy me, and the only purpose I could see them serving would be to either provide a break from Lean’s voice or to jar the listener in preparation for his unorthodox sound. That being said, I liked a good amount of tracks on this album, thought it was a decent project overall, and I appreciate his development. There are a few tracks that will definitely go in rotation for the long term. The over-the-top nature of his previous project, Unknown Death, is lost in Unknown Memory and while it has positive implications, the album lacks some of that original charm by ironically being believable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yung Lean has merit. If you don’t like the rapping or the production, at least appreciate the new concepts of hip-hop he has to bring the the table, the culture that he has appropriated and fashioned into a cult, or simply that he is doing his thing as an 18 year old non-native speaker. This cult of "sadboys" may be doing him no favors in the way that Lil B’s #taskforce annoys the hell out of casual listeners, but he is another interesting case of niche hip-hop and internet fame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: Yung Lean  
Album: Unknown Memory  
Score: "3.0"  
Label: Sky Team  
Release: 2014/9/23  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description><link>http://333vinyl.us/yung-lean-unknown-memory/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">efc97951-a0d0-45b9-80cf-cf2caff2b489</guid><category>reviews</category><dc:creator>Mason Lynaugh</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2014 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>If We Hung Out [002]</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the second edition of &lt;a href="http://333vinyl.us/authors/mason-lynaugh.html"&gt;Mason Lynaugh's&lt;/a&gt; If We Hung Out. This edition features Travi$ Scott, Andrea, and Jimmy Johnson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://333vinyl.us/content/images/2014/11/travi.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/travisscott-2/04-drugs-you-should-try-it"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Travi$ Scott - "Drugs You Should Try It"&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Around two weeks ago, Travi$ Scott released a surprise mixtape. Not only was it a surprise in terms of release–he pulled a Beyonce–but it was also surprisingly put together. Travis Scott, an XXL freshman from 2013, has a lot of enemies for good reasons. He first made ripples throughout the blogosphere when he released &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Vld3uWewvyI"&gt;"Lights"&lt;/a&gt;, and, clearly rife with talent, he continued to generate buzz until he signed a 360 deal as a producer for &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KC-1AaTonTs"&gt;G.O.O.D. Music&lt;/a&gt; and a rapper for &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2uQfbc3NLz8"&gt;Grand Hustle&lt;/a&gt;. However, his entire career has been marred with scandal. He has been attacked for ragging on T.I. and Jay-Z, two of his collaborators, stealing beats, album artwork, and aggravating fans by heedlessly making and subsequently missing release dates. His debut mixtape "Owl Pharaoh", was a testament to his nature. It was messy, uneven, and poorly handled, but it provided the listener with glimpses into his mind and his obvious talent behind the mic and the boards. “Drugs You Should Try It” is haunting and magnificent. The auto-tuned wailing adds a shocking amount of humanity to a poignant sample, and Scott’s rapping has made dramatic improvement. The entire mixtape is worth a listen, especially these  &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dY5F5EsQwqE"&gt;two&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qFbrRXdruv4"&gt;songs&lt;/a&gt;. You’ll find an incredible level of depth to the production, especially in the latter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://333vinyl.us/content/images/2014/11/andrea.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4fhwCvafjYA"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Andrea - "Your Morning"&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Anyone who knows me knows that this is one of my all time favorite songs. By a French producer named Andrea (whether that is pronounced anh-drey-ah or ann-dree-ah is beyond me), who is actually not a female, despite the name. To me, it is the perfect morning song (apt title), and the ideal song for a sunny day in a green field. I use it as an alarm on my iPhone because it makes waking up enjoyable, and I have so much nostalgia attached to it that on rough days it can bring up some emotions, ya feel? Sonically, it reminds me of water flowing through a creek. I’m sitting there adjacent two a pair of stones engulfed in moss, and smiling with a childhood friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://333vinyl.us/content/images/2014/11/jimyjohn.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xPgcSFO6qOg"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jimmy Johnson - "Northside"&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: For almost a year the Toronto-based rapper Jimmy Johnson and Austin, Texas producer Eric Dingus have been making relatively silent moves above the border. Affiliated with the label "Prime", Johnson and Dingus have been inching into the inner circle of Drake’s imprint OVO, and with the title of Drake’s 4th studio effort inspired by Jimmy Johnson, popularizer of the term “The 6”, it seems they have cemented their place. Jimmy Johnson is a fairly middle of the line rapper, but when he combines his vocals with auto-tune and a signature Dingus beat, he does what many auto-tune proficinatos does and becomes more of an instrument than an MC. “Northside” is his best effort yet, with a gritty beat and an infectious chorus, while his debut mixtape some has &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=j-4uWvz3bJk"&gt;gems&lt;/a&gt; as well (the mixtape is fairly good and is definitely worth a few listens). Dingus as well, is someone to watch. I give him until Drake’s next album (which I assume will include his production) to blow up even more than he already has. After &lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/octobersveryown/octobers-very-own-presents-haw-eric-dingus-mixtape"&gt;performing&lt;/a&gt; at OVO’s Houston Appreciation Weekend, and being featured on the OVO blog &lt;a href="http://octobersveryown.blogspot.com/2013/11/drake-worst-behavior-eric-dingus-remix.html"&gt;multiple times&lt;/a&gt;, his remixes are getting serious traffic. His label, Dream Sequence Records, is working on assembling a roster and already has reached some &lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/dream-sequence-records/dowrong-shooters-prod-eric"&gt;talent&lt;/a&gt;. Jimmy Johnson and Eric Dingus should definitely be on your radar.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://333vinyl.us/if-we-hung-out-002/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">373b181c-e2eb-45b9-b749-87e48f0e6088</guid><category>articles</category><category>if we hung out</category><dc:creator>Mason Lynaugh</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>If We Hung Out [001]</title><description>&lt;p&gt;My name is Mason Lynaugh and I will occasionally be contributing to 333vinyl. My musical tastes include Ben’s, but are more concerned with the most recent developments in hip hop - whether it be drill, coastal, trap, or slip-hop - so I will focus mainly on what has been blaring through my speakers on its path to being overplayed. I’m planning on doing periodical entries under the terrible title “if we hung out” because “songs I would make you listen to if we hung out” was a bit worse, and the people who do hang out with me would attest to its accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="more"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://333vinyl.us/content/images/2014/11/kanye.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r4NTDoPQ4mU"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kanye West - All Day (Remake)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: A triumphant victory for the lovely people over at KTT (or &lt;a href="http://333vinyl.us/ktt.jpg"&gt;KanyeToThe&lt;/a&gt;, a forum I endearingly refer to as the 4chan of hip hop) came the day in which someone announced they had a leak of the impending single from Kanye’s untitled seventh solo album. Ironically, this “leak” with the sound quality of something recorded on a graphing calculator triggered an infuriated Kanye to retreat back to Mexico and re-record for an album already rumored to be complete. Nonetheless, since I am part of that seeming minority that doesn’t mind Kanye’s rants, debauchery, or wife, and enjoys his music, I love this remake. Despite being full of mumbling, filler freestyle, unfinished lines, and of shoebox audio quality, it still bumps in the whip, dog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://333vinyl.us/content/images/2014/11/ilm.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HRQyg8RHvIQ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I LOVE MAKONNEN - I Don’t Sell Molly No More&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: ILM has recently received an unprecedented amount of attention for a singer who wails over beats churned out by ATL’s trap oligarchy while &lt;a href="http://www.foxylounge.com/IMG/jpg/i_love_makonnen_tumblr_mcxyf4addm1qlcgcbo1_500-2.jpg"&gt;undeniably resembling a plush toy in appearance&lt;/a&gt;. This is result of current king of rap Drake remixing his fantastic song &lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/octobersveryown/makonnen-ft-drake-tuesday"&gt;“Club Going Up On A Tuesday”&lt;/a&gt;.  “I Don’t Sell” is a grimy gem amongst ballads about mutual infidelity from his &lt;a href="http://www.hotnewhiphop.com/ilovemakonnen-i-love-makonnen-ep-new-mixtape.114225.html"&gt;self-titled EP&lt;/a&gt;, and is one of those songs that people “listen to as a joke” but show definite signs of enjoyment when it is played (think &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JxLS-cpgbe0"&gt;“Dolce and Gabanna”&lt;/a&gt;). I personally love ILM and look forward to his growth as an artist now that he has garnered some limelight a la &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OmHW9IzZYzU"&gt;Migos&lt;/a&gt;. No, I don’t care that you think he sounds like &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iq_d8VSM0nw"&gt;IceJJFish&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://333vinyl.us/content/images/2014/11/rustie.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_mO2VcJAkOw"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rustie - Attak (feat. Danny Brown)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: This is one of those songs that you may have already burnt out on if you’re a self-identifying “hip hop head”, into the contemporary EDM scene, or someone who lurks on Soundcloud. “Attak” marks the fourth collaboration between the two, and I see it as rivaling the incredible &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=22eSJgqxnX4"&gt;“Side B (Dope Song)"&lt;/a&gt; in quality. If you like Danny Brown, Rustie, Electronic music, and/or rap (that should be most everyone), this might tickle your pickle a little. Definitely a party starter up there with the Young Thug cut &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=34LyiriE6eo"&gt;“Old English”&lt;/a&gt; (also a must-listen).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://333vinyl.us/content/images/2014/11/mustard.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.howflyhiphop.com/2014/08/11/dj-mustard-face-down-download-mp3-lil-wayne-big-sean/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Face down (feat. Lil Wayne, Lil Boosie, Big Sean, YG)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Say what you will about DJ Mustard, I stand by my position that he has carved a ubiquitous sound and is deserving of all success. Some may get annoyed by the “aye aye aye” and the way that he uses the same sample kit across his entire discography, but those sounds have some parasitic quality that will infect its way to the top 40. “Face Down” comes from his rudimentary debut album 10 Summers, yet is anything but. It’s a classic love story - “she like her ass tooted up and her face down” with yet another verse from a Lil Wayne who is making admirable progress in &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VmddPo_c2oE"&gt;proving he’s still got it&lt;/a&gt;. However, the real standout here is Big Sean:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Oh my God, I’m in love with a porn star  
I’m in love with a foreign car, they both topless  
I done tricked off a gold Rolle wrist watch  
Man, I’m tired of dealing with these h--- but my d--- not  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://333vinyl.us/content/images/2014/11/mensa.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5jUGAVUwhRU"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Down On My Luck - Vic Mensa&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: By this point everyone knows Disclosure from &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=93ASUImTedo"&gt;“Latch”&lt;/a&gt;, but this Disclosure-produced song hasn’t gotten the love it deserves. I have trouble determining whether it’s alliance lies with EDM or rap, but those familiar with Vic Mensa know how his catalog dabbles in expansive &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZLp7M5SMBkQ"&gt;sonic&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gbcyfRztHmw"&gt;palettes&lt;/a&gt;. “Down On My Luck” is coupled with a clever Groundhog Day-inspired music video that serves as the cherry on top of one of my favorite jams for late drives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://333vinyl.us/content/images/2014/11/trae.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=D2IfOEp5iyE"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trae Tha Truth - Try Me (feat. Young Thug)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: I think Young Thug is the most interesting rapper making noise right now, and he is my second favorite rapper (behind Drake). He’s doing things that are just weird, and reaching commercial success &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5-0kZ_jeIHI"&gt;where other oddballs like Lil B couldn’t&lt;/a&gt;. His charisma and shrill, drawling flow permeate through a song until he owns it &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=etfIdtm-OC8"&gt;whether he is “featured” or not&lt;/a&gt;. Case in point, “Try Me” shows Young Thug partnering with the typically forgettable H-town hero to craft a contender for banger of the year.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://333vinyl.us/if-we-hung-out-001/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6c32bcae-6482-42ce-9515-845d6891fe8c</guid><category>articles</category><category>if we hung out</category><dc:creator>Mason Lynaugh</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2014 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>