<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Ben Bailey - 333vinyl</title><description>The name of this site is 333vinyl. That's what it's about.</description><link>http://333vinyl.us/</link><generator>Ghost 0.5</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 21:47:26 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://333vinyl.us/author/benbailey/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>333vinyl Best Of 2014</title><description>&lt;h2 id="benbaileystopalbums"&gt;Ben Bailey's Top Albums&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spoon - &lt;em&gt;They Want My Soul&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt;
An outstanding album from an outstandingly consistent band.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;St. Vincent - &lt;em&gt;St. Vincent&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt;
St. Vincent's best and bravest work yet.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flying Lotus - &lt;em&gt;You're Dead!&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt;
A future jazz masterpiece.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cloud Nothings - &lt;em&gt;Here And Nowhere Else&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt;
Even better and more concise than &lt;em&gt;Attack On Memory&lt;/em&gt;.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Iceage - &lt;em&gt;Plowing Into The Field Of Love&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt;
The post-punk band takes a dark western turn.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The New Pornographers - &lt;em&gt;Brill Bruisers&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt;
The best New Pornographers album since &lt;em&gt;Twin Cinema&lt;/em&gt;.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TV On The Radio - &lt;em&gt;Seeds&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt;
A great comeback album from the band after their bassist died after the recording of &lt;em&gt;Nine Types of Light&lt;/em&gt;.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parquet Courts - &lt;em&gt;Content Nausea&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt;
The second and better of two albums this band released this year. The title track is a standout, but the whole album is full of complex meditations on modern anxieties.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ought - &lt;em&gt;More Than Any Other Day&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt;
One of the most innovative new bands this year. The vocals and lyrics are Byrne-esque.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Antlers - &lt;em&gt;Familiars&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt;
Not quite as good as their previous two albums, &lt;em&gt;Hospice&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Burst Apart&lt;/em&gt;, but still a great album with an excellent vocal performance. Incorporates horns nicely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id="benbaileystoptracks"&gt;Ben Bailey's Top Tracks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"I'm Not Part of Me" - Cloud Nothings  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"I Wanna Get Better" - Bleachers  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Little Fang" - Avey Tare's Slasher Flicks  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"The Lord's Favorite" - Iceage  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"War On the East Coast" - The New Pornographers  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Do You" - Spoon  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"New Calm Pt. 2" - Ought  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"NEW DORP. NEW YORK" - SBTRKT ft. Ezra Koenig  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Winter" - TV On The Radio  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Never Catch Me" - Flying Lotus ft. Kendrick Lamar  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Mr Noah" - Panda Bear  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Content Nausea" - Parquet Courts  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Birth In Reverse" - St. Vincent  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Twelve Feet Deep" - The Front Bottoms  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Parade" - The Antlers  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Disco//Very" - Warpaint  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Salad Days" - Mac DeMarco  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Every Other Freckle" - Alt-J  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Art School" - Frankie Cosmos  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"How Can You Really" - Foxygen  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Shelter Song" - Temples  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Are You What You Want To Be?" - Foster The People  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Who Needs You" - The Orwells  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Water Fountain" - tUnE-yArDs  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"They Dated Steadily" - Mink Mussel Creek  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Happy Idiot" - TV On The Radio  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Lazaretto" - Jack White  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"The Great Unknown" - Jukebox the Ghost  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"2 is 8" - Lone  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Flesh War" - Total Control&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id="gregdubinstopalbums"&gt;Greg Dubin's Top Albums&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Literature - &lt;em&gt;Chorus&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run the Jewels - &lt;em&gt;Run the Jewels 2&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Menzingers - &lt;em&gt;Rented World&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pete Cannon &amp;amp; Dr. Syntax - &lt;em&gt;Killer Combo!&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Andrew Jackson Jihad - &lt;em&gt;Christmas Island&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fishboy - &lt;em&gt;An Elephant&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kitty - &lt;em&gt;Impatiens&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vanilla - &lt;em&gt;Sweet Talk&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rustie - &lt;em&gt;Green Language&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backtrack - &lt;em&gt;Lost in Life&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id="gregdubinstoptracks"&gt;Greg Dubin's Top Tracks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rustie feat. Danny Brown – "Attak"  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run the Jewels – "Oh My Darling Don't Cry"  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jam Baxter – "Leash"  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Menzingers – "Transient Love"  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fishboy – "I'm a Ghost"  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pete Cannon &amp;amp; Dr. Syntax feat. Jman &amp;amp; Eva Lazarus – "Weed and Ale"  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Andrew Jackson Jihad – "Deathlessness"  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ScHoolBoy Q feat. Kendrick Lamar – "Collard Greens"  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Half Life (Distance and Riz MC) – "Subtle"  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Joey Bada$$ - "Christ Conscious"  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Literature – "New Jacket"  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kitty - "Marijuana"  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backtrack – "Lost in Life"  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vanilla – "Sweet Talk"  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vic Mensa – "Feel That"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id="flanneryrollinstopalbums"&gt;Flannery Rollins' Top Albums&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alex G - &lt;em&gt;DSU&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gerard Way - &lt;em&gt;Hesitant Alien&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flying Lotus - &lt;em&gt;You're Dead!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mac Demarco - &lt;em&gt;Salad Days&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Joyce Manor - &lt;em&gt;Never Hungover Again&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Hotelier - &lt;em&gt;Home, Like Noplace Is There&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frankie Cosmos - &lt;em&gt;Zentropy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cyberbully Mom Club - &lt;em&gt;Outdoor Activities&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="masonlynaughstopalbums"&gt;Mason Lynaugh's Top Albums&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;YG - &lt;em&gt;My Krazy Life&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I Love Makonnen - &lt;em&gt;I Love Makonnen EP&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dowrong and Eric Dingus - &lt;em&gt;The Dowrong EP&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run the Jewels - &lt;em&gt;RTJ2&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vince Staples - &lt;em&gt;Hell Can Wait&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rich Gang - &lt;em&gt;Tha Tour Pt. 1&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Travi$ - &lt;em&gt;Days Before Rodeo&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ratking - &lt;em&gt;So It Goes&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Freddie Gibbs and Madlib - &lt;em&gt;Piñata&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sir Michael Rocks - &lt;em&gt;Banco&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honorable mentions: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various Artists - &lt;em&gt;The Guardians of the Galaxy Soundtrack&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Father - &lt;em&gt;Young Hot Ebony&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><link>http://333vinyl.us/333vinyl-best-of-2014/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">002d9053-a5ce-4218-b352-180a489700ae</guid><category>best-of-2014</category><dc:creator>Ben Bailey</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 22:20:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The New Pornographers - Brill Bruisers</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://333vinyl.us/content/images/2014/11/the_new_pornographers-brill_bruisers.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the best New Pornographers album since &lt;em&gt;Twin Cinema&lt;/em&gt;. The Canadian supergroup excels in celebratory music, and after two somewhat-lackluster offerings with a darker sound, &lt;em&gt;Brill Bruisers&lt;/em&gt; is a triumphant return. Frontman A.C. Newman described the record as "a celebration record," and the band follows through completely on that promise, boasting titles such as "Champions of Red Wine" and "Dancehall Domine."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The album begins with the title track, a single with a masterful ear-worm of a wordless chorus. Two lighter celebratory songs follow that sound like they could be from earlier New Pornographers albums, "Champions of Red Wine" and "Fantasy Fools."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next comes my personal favorite track, "War on the East Coast." Its &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WMcumbSMY_8"&gt;brilliant 90s-Britpop-style video&lt;/a&gt; combined with Dan Bejar's unique vocal stylings make for four minutes of up-tempo bliss. It's one of those songs that feels like you've been waiting to hear for a long time. The song transitions smoothly into "Backstairs," which starts with slow, vocoder vocals but eventually breaks out into one of the band's grooviest verses. Neko Case's golden voice propels along the following "Marching Orders," which concludes one of the strongest trios the band has recorded. "Another Drug Deal of the Heart" serves as a quick, fun epilogue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not to say that there aren't a few misses on the album. "Born With a Sound," another Bejar track, sounds a lot like a watered-down "War on the East Coast." The following "Wide Eyes" has its moments but largely falls flat, with the band coming across as a New Pornographers cover band.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By contrast, "Dancehall Domine" is the band doing what they do best, and has a classic New Pornographers sound. "Spidyr" is a bit of an oddball, but fits in well with "Hi-Rise," both providing a lush respite from the celebrations. Closer "You Tell Me Where" is a hopeful song, and provides a perfect refrain to end the album.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While &lt;em&gt;Brill Bruisers&lt;/em&gt; never quite reaches the highs of &lt;em&gt;Mass Romantic&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;The Electric Version&lt;/em&gt;, it's the best New Pornographers record in a long time, and it's a great album for celebration. It's a triumphant return for a triumphant band.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: The New Pornographers  
Album: Brill Bruisers  
Score: 4.0  
Label: Matador  
Release: 2014/08/26  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description><link>http://333vinyl.us/the-new-pornographers-brill-bruisers/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">48e01322-7281-4123-916f-620d2143cc76</guid><category>reviews</category><dc:creator>Ben Bailey</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>What I've Been Listening To [001]</title><description>&lt;p&gt;This week I finally went through a large portion of all the albums on my "to-listen" list. These are the ones I'm currently enjoying. Interestingly enough, seven of the nine albums are debuts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://333vinyl.us/content/images/2014/11/collage.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beach House - &lt;em&gt;Bloom&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: This is a great album that took me a few listens to get in to. It's not groundbreaking, but it's incredible high-quality and accessible dream pop. Good for sunrises, sunsets, and dusk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DIIV - &lt;em&gt;Oshin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Maybe the best way to describe this album is a rainy day at the beach. Great dreamy jam sound, reminiscient of Real Estate. "Doused" is a standout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Jesus and Mary Chain - &lt;em&gt;Psychocandy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Slacker shoegaze, or shoegaze before there was shoegaze. The JAMC's noisy guitars and airy vocals paved the way for My Bloody Valentine just three years later. And they didn't care. This is some of the catchiest and most indifferent noise you can get.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joy Division - &lt;em&gt;Unknown Pleasures&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: One of the best post-punk albums. Ian Curtis' baritone matches perfectly with the themes of isolation prevalent in his lyrics. The guitar and bass propell the songs through they airy abyss created by the drums. I'm going to listen to the follow-up &lt;em&gt;Closer&lt;/em&gt; soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Metric - &lt;em&gt;Old World Underground, Where Are You Now?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Metric's debut album. It sounds a lot different from their later work, but it has a good punk vibe. Creates a unique nervous atmosphere. I think it's about robots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Rapture - &lt;em&gt;Echoes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: One of the first true dance-punk albums. The Rapture also experiment with modern indie rock. Highlights include the Strokes-esque title track and lead single "House of Jealous Lovers." Definitely check this out if you're into dance-punk or early 2000s garage rock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ride - &lt;em&gt;Nowhere&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: This album is possibly the best that shoegaze has to offer outside of My Bloody Valentine. Opener "Seagull" is iconic, and the other tracks that fill out the album's short 39-minute runtime are almost as good. More accessible than some of the other popular shoegaze albums.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sonic Youth - &lt;em&gt;Daydream Nation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: "Teen Age Riot" is a masterpiece, the best track on what most say is Sonic Youth's best work. The album perfectly balances noise and rock, creating a unique sound that new indie acts are still trying to emulate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sunny Day Real Estate - &lt;em&gt;Diary&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: A definitive emo album. Not to be confused with A Sunny Day In Glasgow. Great guitar and vocal work. If you like "In Circles," you'll like the album. Perfect for warm summer night listening.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://333vinyl.us/what-ive-been-listening-to-001/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">b870f17d-3216-479f-b95f-00bb67cdcabc</guid><category>articles</category><category>what I've been listening to</category><dc:creator>Ben Bailey</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2014 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>of Montreal - Hissing Fauna, Are You The Destroyer?</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://333vinyl.us/content/images/2014/11/of_montreal-hissing_fauna-_are_you_the_destroyer-1.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;of Montreal, part of the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elephant_Six"&gt;Elephant 6 collective&lt;/a&gt; that spawned (among others) Neutral Milk Hotel and The Olivia Tremor Control, has released twelve albums in sixteen years. While not as consistent in quality as, say, Spoon, of Montreal's substantial output has yielded several magnificent albums. &lt;em&gt;Hissing Fauna, Are You The Destroyer?&lt;/em&gt; is of Montreal's finest work, an impressive struggle with depression and identity backed by infectious melodies and grooves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This album is a masterpiece. The first half is quintessential quirky indie pop, and the second is glorious glam-pop. The shift is pulled off seamlessly during the album's twelve-minute centerpiece "The Past Is a Grotesque Animal," in which Kevin Barnes (who wrote the album himself) transforms into a black transsexual (&lt;code&gt;I got my Georgie Fruit on / He's a dark mutation / For my demented past time&lt;/code&gt;). He keeps this alter ego for the rest of &lt;em&gt;Hissing Fauna&lt;/em&gt; and of Montreal's next three albums, which are named after the last lines of "Faberge Falls For Shuggie" (&lt;code&gt;Skeletal lamping, the controller sphere, false priest&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The album begins with "Suffer For Fashion," which might be the most straightforwardly catchy song on the album. It has a bit of an early Arcade Fire feel. The next two songs are similarly catchy, trippy indie pop. One of the best tracks on the album is lead single "Heimdalsgate Like a Promethean Curse," a plea with serotonin to not make Barnes "sick again." "Gronlandic Edit" and "A Sentence of Sorts in Kongsvinger" deal with depression, isolation, and identity crisis (&lt;code&gt;I spent the winter with my nose buried in a book / While trying to restructure my character / Cause it had become vile to its creator&lt;/code&gt;). "The Past Is A Grotesque Animal" follows directly after, an epic cathartic freakout. From its ashes rises "Bunny Ain't No Kind Of Rider," a more lighthearted put-down of a club patron's come-on (which he shoots down due to her lack of soul power). "Faberge Falls For Shuggie" is of Montreal at its grooviest and trippiest. "Labrynthian Pomp" is another power-glam tour de force, beginning with &lt;code&gt;How you wanna hate a thing / When you are so inferior&lt;/code&gt;. It flows quite nicely into the similar "She's A Rejector." "We Were Born the Mutants Again With Leafling" is a slightly calmer, more melodic and thoughtful ending to a fantastic album.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Barnes' lyrics contain the key to &lt;em&gt;Hissing Fauna&lt;/em&gt;'s success. &lt;code&gt;We just want to emote until we're dead / I know we suffer for fashion or whatever&lt;/code&gt;, implying that we suffer because it's fashionable. Barnes is notorious for his dry humor, and it's at its strongest here. The album features lines such as &lt;code&gt;Saw her at Go kissing girls, what a shock / I said you must be an artist&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Somehow you've red-rovered the Gestapo circling my heart&lt;/code&gt; At the same time, he is honest to a fault and inexplicably clever. Throughout the album, Barnes struggles through chemical depression and the deterioration of a relationship, and does so in a brilliant, weird, and yet relatable way. Few songwriters can be as simultaneously odd and familiar as Kevin Barnes, and he is at his best on this album.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hissing Fauna, Are You The Destroyer?&lt;/em&gt; is an essential listen for anyone who has struggled with chemicals, has a dry wit, or just loves damn good indie pop songs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: of Montreal  
Album: Hissing Fauna, Are You The Destroyer?  
Score: 5.0  
Label: Polyvinyl  
Release: 2007/01/23  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description><link>http://333vinyl.us/of-montreal-hissing-fauna-are-you-the-destroyer/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">c9d40a95-b55f-40b9-a8d8-6b172209a8cc</guid><category>reviews</category><dc:creator>Ben Bailey</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2014 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Death Cab For Cutie - Transatlanticism</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://333vinyl.us/content/images/2014/11/death_cab_for_cutie-transatlanticism-1.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Transatlanticism&lt;/em&gt; is widely considered Death Cab For Cutie's magnum opus. It's Death Cab's fourth studio album of seven, but probably the first album that comes to someone's mind when they talk about the band. "Sound of Settling," which frontman Ben Gibbard originally didn't want to include on the album, has become one of Death Cab's biggest hits. The rough concept album about distance and its effect on relationships is beloved by critics, teenagers, and music enthusiasts alike, and is considered an instant classic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Transatlanticism&lt;/em&gt; begins with "The New Year," which describes Dismemberment-Plan-style disillusionment with new year's festivities. It sets the tone nicely for what will follow, as does "Lightness," which flows nicely into the standout "Title and Registration."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The song starts with Gibbard cleverly proposing a change of the name "glove compartment," because the only things inside are disappointment and regret. The drum sound here is instantly memorable, and drives Gibbard's voice and the equally distinctive riff forward, a common musical theme across &lt;em&gt;Transatlanticism&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Expo '86" artfully turns an innocent, pleasant riff into a symbol of grating repetition, all while maintaining its saccharine facade. Lead single "Sound of Settling" is Death Cab at their catchiest, matched only by &lt;em&gt;Plans&lt;/em&gt; single "Crooked Teeth." It doesn't fit perfectly with the rest of these songs, but it serves its purpose as a nice introductory point to the band and acts as an upbeat catharsis of sorts before the harder-hitting second half of the album takes over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the album provides some of the strongest tracks, revolving around the titular centerpiece, a beautiful seven-minute treatise against distance and a plea for closeness. By the time "A Lack of Color" comes on, you, like Gibbard, know it's over but don't want it to end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrow Stairs&lt;/em&gt; was always my favorite Death Cab album until I read along while listening through this. I still maintain the (unpopular) opinion that &lt;em&gt;Narrow Stairs&lt;/em&gt; is Death Cab's most instrumentally interesting work, but Gibbard's lyrics on this album push it above and beyond any of the band's efforts since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Transatlanticism&lt;/em&gt; is by no means an uplifting album, but it doesn't force gloom upon you. Instead, the album sinks inside you, until you come to feel what Death Cab want you to feel. Gibbard doesn't attempt to hide his true meaning in complex wordplay--in fact, he's quite happy to spell out what he's experiencing. He does so artfully however, coming across as earnest instead of inane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you really &lt;em&gt;listen&lt;/em&gt; to this album, you begin to know it like a friend. It's shy at first, but once you strike up a conversation with it, and it tells you all it knows about young love and separation, you don't want to stop talking. &lt;em&gt;Transatlanticism&lt;/em&gt; truly is Death Cab For Cutie at their best. With warm guitar melodies, distinctive drumming, and lyrics that will be scrawled in notebook margins for years to come, it definitely deserves your time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: Death Cab For Cutie  
Album: Transatlanticism  
Score: 4.5  
Label: Barsuk  
Release: 2003/10/07  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description><link>http://333vinyl.us/death-cab-for-cutie-transatlanticism/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6f7e6952-5871-492e-874f-e8b00959fb17</guid><dc:creator>Ben Bailey</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2014 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Broken Social Scene - You Forgot It In People</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://333vinyl.us/content/images/2014/11/broken_social_scene-you_forgot_it_in_people-1.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took me a few listens to get into &lt;em&gt;You Forgot It In People&lt;/em&gt;. The first time I downloaded it, I skimmed through the songs. Upon not finding any immediate hits on what was billed as a pop album, I decided to give it a more thorough listen on a later date. Now, nearly a year after first listening to it, I decided to give it another chance, and another, and another. There is so much more to this album than I initially thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe the most amazing thing about Broken Social Scene is how many incredible bands the supergroup contains. Members of Metric, Feist, and Stars are all present on &lt;em&gt;You Forgot It In People&lt;/em&gt;, and it shows. The band manages to put each individual's talent to good use. This brilliant album is disjointed enough not to be repetitive, but cohesive enough to not lose the listener's attention, even throughout the several instrumentals that are scattered through the track listing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The standout tracks here are definitely fan-favorites "Anthems For A Seventeen Year-Old Girl" and "Lover's Spit." "Anthems" is a stunning piece, consisting of soft banjo plucks and strings drifting around Emily Haines of Metric's looping, warped vocals. The repetition is key as Haines rolls through several choice phrases, letting each resonate before pleading &lt;code&gt;Park that car, drop that phone, sleep on the floor, dream about me&lt;/code&gt; again and again until you want to do just that. The phrase gets gently imprinted in your ears, becoming a sort of mantra which stays in your head through the instrumentals which follow shortly after. "Lover's Spit" is one of the oddest and bitterest ballads in recent memory, and when paired with "Anthems" creates a potent mixture of lonely longing that hasn't been matched in years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the album doesn't hit quite as heavily, but when combined with the standout tracks, &lt;em&gt;You Forgot It In People&lt;/em&gt; is easier to relate to than most pop albums. While so much pop is about common problems, it often feels like the musicians are removed and distant. Here, Broken Social Scene is messaging you late at night, because they know exactly how you feel and they want to let you know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think what stands out to me the most about &lt;em&gt;You Forgot It In People&lt;/em&gt; is that Broken Social Scene managed to make music for teenagers without being simplistic. The lyrics oscillate between simple, powerful mantras and dark, visceral, abrasive metaphors, but not once does the album come off as condescending or fake. Instead, Broken Social Scene is holding your hair back when you vomit from drinking too much trying to forget, and laughing with you when you laugh at yourself the next morning. You just want to return the favor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: Broken Social Scene  
Album: You Forgot It In People  
Score: 4.5  
Label: Arts &amp;amp; Crafts  
Release: 2002/10/15  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description><link>http://333vinyl.us/broken-social-scene-you-forgot-it-in-people/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">7e4a83cd-7e1c-444b-a1df-55cc9f54f6cd</guid><category>reviews</category><dc:creator>Ben Bailey</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2014 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Modern Lovers - The Modern Lovers</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://333vinyl.us/content/images/2014/11/the_modern_lovers-the_modern_lovers-1.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Modern Lovers&lt;/em&gt; starts off with Richman counting &lt;code&gt;1-2-3-4-5-6!&lt;/code&gt;, a twist on the classic four-count that begins so many songs. It's a little familiar, a little odd, and strangely endearing, all threads that run deep in the band's definitive proto-punk opus as well as in the work of the countless artists that were inspired by the album.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="more"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first I heard of The Modern Lovers was James Murphy's name-drop in "Losing My Edge." I've been working my way through all (well, most) of the bands he mentions, and the Modern Lovers Wikipedia page intrigued me, so I got the album. As soon as the first notes hit, I could tell that I was going to witness something unique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The album begins with "Roadrunner," The Modern Lovers' biggest hit and easily their catchiest song. The groove established on this opening track carries on through the rest of the album, creating a driving force that doesn't pause until "Hospital." A lot has been said about this one already, so I'll just add that it's one of the best road-trip songs ever written. The second track, "Astral Plane," sounds like a missed connection in a hazy basement backed by a trademark Modern Lovers seventies groove--the atmosphere the band manages to create here is palpable. Unfortunately, the rest of the tracks don't stand out as much, especially in comparison to "Roadrunner." However, the band exchanges a lack of standouts for consistency, and the album is so well-executed that the trade off is worthwhile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One key feature of the album is Jerry Harrison's keyboard. It shows up in all the right places, propelling "Roadrunner," "Pablo Picasso," and "Modern World" but hanging back on the guitar-driven "She Cracked" and "Old World." Bassist Ernie Brooks contributes similarly, displaying the ability to play in several different styles depending on what fits the song best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This album is definitive proto-punk, but what really sets it apart for me is the heart-on-sleeve nature of the lyrics. When Jonathan Richman rants about Picasso's womanizing ways in the incredibly clever "Pablo Picasso," (which features the refrain &lt;code&gt;Pablo Picasso never got called an asshole&lt;/code&gt;) you get the sense that Richman has been called an asshole too often. Even when Richman cheesily spells out the title of "Girlfriend," he sounds earnest and wide-eyed instead of inane. This is particularly impressive considering the nasal sneer he carries throughout the duration of the album, creating a masterful contrast of punk power and pop vulnerability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give &lt;em&gt;The Modern Lovers&lt;/em&gt; a listen. It's a classic collection of strong songs, and there's never a dull moment. It's well worth counting past four for the opportunity to experience the roots of punk taking shape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: The Modern Lovers  
Album: The Modern Lovers  
Score: 4.0  
Label: Beserkley  
Release: 1976/08  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description><link>http://333vinyl.us/the-modern-lovers-the-modern-lovers/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">17258e39-e5e8-4f95-9c9b-3cef930bc655</guid><category>reviews</category><dc:creator>Ben Bailey</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2014 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Le Tigre - Le Tigre</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://333vinyl.us/content/images/2014/11/le_tigre-le_tigre-2.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Le Tigre is perhaps best known as Kathleen Hanna's other band. Hanna was the frontwoman of Bikini Kill (which kickstarted the riot grrrl movement), has had several documentaries made about her, and (fun-fact) is married to Ad-Rock. But I only heard about Le Tigre yesterday while looking for dance-punk bands. I had no idea Hanna was involved until the first verse of the first (and perhaps best) song, "Deceptacon," which tears down preconceptions, sets expectations, and takes a shot at pop music in five lines: &lt;code&gt;Wanna disco? / Wanna see me disco? / Let me hear you depoliticize my rhyme. / One! Two! Three! Four! /  You got what you been asking for.&lt;/code&gt; It's a classic Hanna takedown, one which sets the tone nicely for the rest of &lt;em&gt;Le Tigre&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="more"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's this spirit which lies at the heart of the album, and its strengths. Hanna is at her best as a lyricist when she's telling you what's wrong and how it should be. While "Deceptacon" is the standout track of the album, it's closely followed by "Hot Topic," a song about pop music that builds up to a "Losing My Edge"-style list of strong female artists that would take ages to explore. Third track "What's Yr Take On Cassavetes?," in which the band debates the merit of John Cassavetes, is also memorable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The album never quite regains the dance-punk spark of the first three tracks, but the rest is still an enjoyable listen, especially for those who can't get past Bikini Kill's hardcore influences. Hanna's spirit and message infuse even the weaker tracks with an energy that carries them to greater heights. Whenever the songs begin to feel bland and uninteresting, Hanna manages to pull out a clever lyric or harsh statement that directs the listener's attention front and center once again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps &lt;em&gt;Le Tigre&lt;/em&gt;'s greatest trait is its ability to deliver punk spirit entwined with shockingly catchy dance numbers. The album may not be stuffed with conventional dance or punk numbers, but it's a brilliant and vicious strike against oppression and dull pop that will linger in your head for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: Le Tigre  
Album: Le Tigre  
Score: 4.0  
Label: Mr. Lady  
Release: 1999/10/26  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description><link>http://333vinyl.us/le-tigre-le-tigre/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">3d479fdf-2dce-455c-880d-469041aea302</guid><category>reviews</category><dc:creator>Ben Bailey</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2014 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Spoon - They Want My Soul</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://333vinyl.us/content/images/2014/11/spoon-they_want_my_soul-1.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the few years I was discovering new music on my own, I would play the most recent album on Rdio to see if I liked a band. In 2011, Spoon's latest was the divisive &lt;em&gt;Transference&lt;/em&gt;. It's still one of my favorite Spoon albums, and I was never a huge fan of &lt;em&gt;GA GA GA GA GA&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Gimme Fiction&lt;/em&gt; (both enjoyable listens, but neither stood out to me). It took me another few years to discover the breakthrough &lt;em&gt;Kill the Moonlight&lt;/em&gt;, which remains my favorite Spoon album. &lt;em&gt;They Want My Soul&lt;/em&gt;, however, is the now-mature band's best offering since their career-standout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The album begins with first single "Rent I Pay," which sets the tone wonderfully for the rest of the album. It's relatively straightforward but packs the confident groove we've come to expect from Spoon. "Inside Out," a late-night slow-burner (accompanied with a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IpT5SBg1Mmk"&gt;trippy video&lt;/a&gt;) follows directly after, creating Spoon's strongest one-two punch since 2002's &lt;em&gt;Kill the Moonlight&lt;/em&gt; ("Small Stakes"/"The Way We Get By"). The acoustic guitar/bass/drum combination on the next three tracks prove that Spoon haven't lost the ability to groove, which was front-and-center on &lt;em&gt;GA GA GA GA GA&lt;/em&gt;, even managing to surpass some of the album's finest tracks. "Do You,"" in particular, sounds like an improved version of "Don't You Evah."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second half of the album is where Spoon shakes things up a bit. "Outlier" sounds like Arctic Monkeys' "Fireside" with better lyrical themes and more well-placed digs at Garden State (&lt;code&gt;I remember you walked out of Garden State / You had taste, you had taste, you had taste&lt;/code&gt;). The title track stands out as one of the most "daytime"-sounding tracks an album that sounds most comfortable playing through car speakers late at night. "I Just Don't Understand" is a great cover that ties in nicely to "Let Me Be Mine"; the latter is some of Britt Daniel's better plainspoken, more emotional writing. "New York Kiss" completes the sentimental trilogy, ending on a note worthy of the rest of the album.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Admittedly, much of the instrumentation doesn't stand out, but this is no surprise. Spoon are remarkably consistent. True to form, the way the band combines all their tight, crisp, relatively simple pieces together remains their greatest strength. Some tracks sound quite similar, but repeated listens reveal intricacies that make each track stand out in its own way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, &lt;em&gt;They Want My Soul&lt;/em&gt; is one of the year's best releases so far, providing exciting, intriguing variations on the classic Spoon sound. Do yourself a favor and listen to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: Spoon  
Album: They Want My Soul  
Score: 4.5  
Label: Loma Vista  
Release: 2014/08/05  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description><link>http://333vinyl.us/spoon-they-want-my-soul/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">3201c4a9-de82-4882-b6cb-babff33ec8b5</guid><category>reviews</category><dc:creator>Ben Bailey</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>