<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>articles - 333vinyl</title><description>The name of this site is 333vinyl. That's what it's about.</description><link>http://333vinyl.us/</link><generator>Ghost 0.5</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 21:47:26 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://333vinyl.us/tag/articles/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>The Saddest//The Baddest: How To Be an Angsty Teen Girl 101: Fall Edition</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I'm Sophie from Whidbey Island in Washington State and I like to pretend I know what's cool. My music taste is pretty broad so I won't go into detail, but I will say I like Dave Matthews Band in a very un-ironic way. Here's what to listen to while smoking, painting nails, and driving home at 5 AM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="more"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: Autre Ne Veut  
Song: Counting  
Album: Anxiety  
Label: Mexican Summer  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Counting," by Brooklyn producer Arthur Ashin (his name only revealed to fans recently, as to protect his identity during his studies in psychology for his masters degree), easily stands out as the most powerful track off of Autre Ne Veut’s February 2013 album Anxiety. Ashin’s delicate falsetto sets him apart from the sea of “bedroom R&amp;amp;B” producers, as well as his use of honking horn section squeaks and heavy groans that make up the underlying beat of "Counting"; so deep they feel almost pelvic. "Counting" is about ends—in particular, the death of Ashin’s grandmother. The falsetto cries out that &lt;code&gt;I’m counting on the idea that you’ll stay alive&lt;/code&gt; and now you understand the pain behind the lyrics, as well as the catharsis behind the anguish turned into soaring vocals and electronic trills. &lt;code&gt;This is not your time to make it out&lt;/code&gt; screams Ashin, imploring vitality to continue in this relationship, in this life, in this season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: Dum Dum Girls  
Song: There Is A Light That Never Goes Out  
Album: He Gets Me High EP  
Label: Sub Pop  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will refrain from claiming to like this cover of The Smiths' joyful lamentation better than the original, but it definitely comes close. Leading lady Kristen “Dee Dee” Gundred's voice is expansive and elastic. The solid strumming of the guitars are unbound and grinding. Gundred’s cover is almost more emotional than the never-outdone Morrissey. I can sense a bit of anger within her soft growl, but when it’s time for the chorus, the famous &lt;code&gt;And if a ten ton truck kills the both of us // to die by your side well the pleasure, the privilege is mine&lt;/code&gt;, the sentiment is soft and lovely, and infuses the melody with the utmost beauty. The guitars concede to the poetry of the song itself and to the vocals of the Dum Dum Girls, which have been uttered with a quite angelic element. The juxtaposition of these sweet female voices with Morrissey's raw songwriting makes this my song choice for my MP3 player whilst passing my college crush on the way across the quad as a way to feel powerful again under their gaze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: Ghost Loft  
Song: Seconds  
Album: Seconds  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Be there in seconds flat // Just tell me where you at// Everywhere you want to go// I’ve been there before// That means he don't need to know&lt;/code&gt; These are the opening lines of "Seconds," by Danny Choi, AKA LA producer Ghost Loft, who has created the ultimate track of nighttime secrecy. The tune itself is straightforward, but it seems to float into the night before the beat comes in. It is steady, and not quite sure of itself, but it evokes the feeling of urban anxiety; essentially fearful and extremely tentative. But the song feels like a journey, possibly to the doorstep of a lover. "Seconds" is dark, yet comforting with the presence of the quiet voice of track, who appeals to the delicacy and urgency of the actions made in the dead of the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: J. Tillman  
Song: Earthly Bodies  
Album: Year in the Kingdom  
Label: Western Vinyl  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could tell you about how I feel about fall: the severing of ties, the loss, the renewal, the journey into the darkness in order to grow and evolve… but I’m sure you’ve discovered what autumn means for yourself, or have read about it in some article about re-organizing your life in time for winter. Anyway, I first heard "Earthly Bodies" in an airport bathroom while taking my significant other to his flight back to England. Knowing I would not see him for a long time I was clearly a mess. I was wiping my eyes in the mirror and heard &lt;code&gt;Let me lay across your crescent spine // Press my belly to the mountainside&lt;/code&gt;. I conjured up the road trip I had just taken with my love: the lazy day by the river in the middle of the still-snow-capped mountains amid the shade of green only seen in the Northwest. I got home a few hours later and thought about starting over at college soon and about the autumn of the Northeast. "Earthly Bodies" played as I fell asleep dreaming about the cold weather and healing my hurting heart. Four months later, as I sit in my dorm room that over looks the burgundy-colored quad, J. Tillman’s ballad to transformation, love lost and found in the pleasure of connections to people and nature, and finding comfort within another person still plays. The fall season continues to change me through music, walks in the forest in the glory of Massachusetts, and nostalgia of summer memories with my boyfriend. &lt;code&gt;Baby, lay your head where we begin and end&lt;/code&gt; Tillman sings, asking us through his soft-spoken, wondering-at-the-world poetry that we remember fall is both the end and the start of the cycle of holding on and letting go.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://333vinyl.us/the-saddestthe-baddest-how-to-be-an-angsty-teen-girl-101-fall-edition/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">62f9d3ef-16f1-4fc8-9e22-8b1e80461c38</guid><category>articles</category><category>the saddest the baddest</category><dc:creator>Sophie Frank</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2014 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Eclectic Essentials [001]</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Hi, I’m Sara and I will be contributing to 333vinyl. My taste includes the foundation of indie rock central to the site in addition to special detail to female vocalists and experimental alternative rock. In the interest of saving everyone’s time, let me guide you, the reader, through four albums that I feel represent my basis and growth as a music fan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://333vinyl.us/content/images/2014/11/collage.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: Britney Spears  
Album: Blackout  
Released: 2007  
First listen: 2007  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do not think I am beginning our relationship on the wrong foot, dear reader. Truly, pop music was the first cement poured into my malleable ears, and it has stuck with me since. My previous music reviews have all been for contemporary pop albums, including Spears’ 2011 album &lt;em&gt;Femme Fatale&lt;/em&gt;. In addition, &lt;em&gt;Blackout&lt;/em&gt; taught me not to judge an album by its artist. Publicity for the album occurred during Spears’ highly publicized personal struggles, heavily affecting sales. This did not stop me from receiving a copy from my obsessed best friend, who told me to give her a chance. The first lesson that &lt;em&gt;Blackout&lt;/em&gt; taught me was to take risks when choosing what music to listen to and to shirk preconceptions and previous opinions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I’ve explained myself: Blackout is a good album. A damn good album, at that. You would think because the only single that truly took off was the controversial “Gimme More”, which was (and is) treated as a joke by the press, the entire album is brainless pop litter. But it’s truly the opposite: &lt;em&gt;Blackout&lt;/em&gt; is revolutionary electro-pop that showcases techniques later adopted and brought into the mainstream by other artists. Most notable is the dubstep-influenced breakdown in “Freakshow,” a full four years before another’s appearance in her record-breaking #1 “Hold It Against Me.” Spears is referred to as the Princess of Pop for a reason—she continually works with producers who break the boundaries and with whom she makes pop history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: Snow Patrol  
Album: Final Straw  
Released: 2003  
First listen: 2009  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, I was turned on to indie rock. My first introduction to the genre was Death Cab for Cutie’s “I Will Possess Your Heart,” which lead me to pursue like-minded artists. Both Death Cab and Snow Patrol had songs on in Wicker Park, a critically-panned film with an incredible motion picture soundtrack. It was there that I discovered pre-“Chasing Cars” Snow Patrol through “How to Be Dead,” a poignant introduction to the kinds of feelings that lead vocalist and songwriter Gary Lightbody evokes. &lt;em&gt;Final Straw&lt;/em&gt; was when I started to identify with lyrics and study the intricacies of them, which is a byproduct of my love for prose in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: Fiona Apple  
Album: Extraordinary Machine  
Released: 2005  
First listen: 2010  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before reaching for &lt;em&gt;Extraordinary Machine&lt;/em&gt;, I had listened to Apple’s previous two albums, having been working through her discography. What intrigued me most about &lt;em&gt;Extraordinary Machine&lt;/em&gt; is that two versions of it exist—a leaked bootleg produced exclusively by Jon Brion and sprinkled with strings, and the official release with completely different arrangements on all but two songs and the added “Parting Gift.” The politics behind the music industry interest me and Machine is a classic representation of the label screwing the artist. In addition, demo and bootleg recordings fascinate me on a basic level: that which we were never supposed to hear has been taken from the vaults so that we may appreciate its existence. Unreleased works thrown into the mainstream are like poetry in a way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: OK Go  
Album: Of the Blue Colour of the Sky  
Released: 2010  
First listen: 2010  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK Go is my favorite band.  It has taken me seven years of exploring music to be able to find a band that represents all that I love about music, and in 2009 I finally found them. Mostly famous for their DIY, one-take music videos, OK Go are also masters of something beautiful: doing whatever the hell they want. After reaching mainstream success with “Here It Goes Again” and much tension, they left their major label and formed their own. Blue Colour is their first independent release and exemplifies their own eclectic taste—funky psychedelics present in “In the Glass” contrast the acoustic beauty of “Last Leaf.” OK Go writes songs about regret, desire, perseverance, and, put succinctly, the essence of life. OK Go represents all that I love about music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all, I look forward to exploring my eclectic music taste with 333vinyl. It truly runs the gamut from &lt;code&gt;I struggle for the words and then give up / My head’s up with the birds on the T-hut&lt;/code&gt; (“Spitting Games” – Snow Patrol) to &lt;code&gt;If I got on top, you're gonna lose your mind&lt;/code&gt; ("Get Naked [I Got a Plan]" – Britney Spears). Follow me on &lt;a href="http://www.last.fm/user/maymayyy"&gt;Last.fm&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.twitter.com/saatuna"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://333vinyl.us/eclectic-essentials-001/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">ac827fda-f339-4508-875f-24d927adc181</guid><category>articles</category><category>eclectic essentials</category><dc:creator>Sara Turner</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2014 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>If We Hung Out [002]</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the second edition of &lt;a href="http://333vinyl.us/authors/mason-lynaugh.html"&gt;Mason Lynaugh's&lt;/a&gt; If We Hung Out. This edition features Travi$ Scott, Andrea, and Jimmy Johnson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://333vinyl.us/content/images/2014/11/travi.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/travisscott-2/04-drugs-you-should-try-it"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Travi$ Scott - "Drugs You Should Try It"&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Around two weeks ago, Travi$ Scott released a surprise mixtape. Not only was it a surprise in terms of release–he pulled a Beyonce–but it was also surprisingly put together. Travis Scott, an XXL freshman from 2013, has a lot of enemies for good reasons. He first made ripples throughout the blogosphere when he released &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Vld3uWewvyI"&gt;"Lights"&lt;/a&gt;, and, clearly rife with talent, he continued to generate buzz until he signed a 360 deal as a producer for &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KC-1AaTonTs"&gt;G.O.O.D. Music&lt;/a&gt; and a rapper for &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2uQfbc3NLz8"&gt;Grand Hustle&lt;/a&gt;. However, his entire career has been marred with scandal. He has been attacked for ragging on T.I. and Jay-Z, two of his collaborators, stealing beats, album artwork, and aggravating fans by heedlessly making and subsequently missing release dates. His debut mixtape "Owl Pharaoh", was a testament to his nature. It was messy, uneven, and poorly handled, but it provided the listener with glimpses into his mind and his obvious talent behind the mic and the boards. “Drugs You Should Try It” is haunting and magnificent. The auto-tuned wailing adds a shocking amount of humanity to a poignant sample, and Scott’s rapping has made dramatic improvement. The entire mixtape is worth a listen, especially these  &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dY5F5EsQwqE"&gt;two&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qFbrRXdruv4"&gt;songs&lt;/a&gt;. You’ll find an incredible level of depth to the production, especially in the latter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://333vinyl.us/content/images/2014/11/andrea.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4fhwCvafjYA"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Andrea - "Your Morning"&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Anyone who knows me knows that this is one of my all time favorite songs. By a French producer named Andrea (whether that is pronounced anh-drey-ah or ann-dree-ah is beyond me), who is actually not a female, despite the name. To me, it is the perfect morning song (apt title), and the ideal song for a sunny day in a green field. I use it as an alarm on my iPhone because it makes waking up enjoyable, and I have so much nostalgia attached to it that on rough days it can bring up some emotions, ya feel? Sonically, it reminds me of water flowing through a creek. I’m sitting there adjacent two a pair of stones engulfed in moss, and smiling with a childhood friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://333vinyl.us/content/images/2014/11/jimyjohn.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xPgcSFO6qOg"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jimmy Johnson - "Northside"&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: For almost a year the Toronto-based rapper Jimmy Johnson and Austin, Texas producer Eric Dingus have been making relatively silent moves above the border. Affiliated with the label "Prime", Johnson and Dingus have been inching into the inner circle of Drake’s imprint OVO, and with the title of Drake’s 4th studio effort inspired by Jimmy Johnson, popularizer of the term “The 6”, it seems they have cemented their place. Jimmy Johnson is a fairly middle of the line rapper, but when he combines his vocals with auto-tune and a signature Dingus beat, he does what many auto-tune proficinatos does and becomes more of an instrument than an MC. “Northside” is his best effort yet, with a gritty beat and an infectious chorus, while his debut mixtape some has &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=j-4uWvz3bJk"&gt;gems&lt;/a&gt; as well (the mixtape is fairly good and is definitely worth a few listens). Dingus as well, is someone to watch. I give him until Drake’s next album (which I assume will include his production) to blow up even more than he already has. After &lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/octobersveryown/octobers-very-own-presents-haw-eric-dingus-mixtape"&gt;performing&lt;/a&gt; at OVO’s Houston Appreciation Weekend, and being featured on the OVO blog &lt;a href="http://octobersveryown.blogspot.com/2013/11/drake-worst-behavior-eric-dingus-remix.html"&gt;multiple times&lt;/a&gt;, his remixes are getting serious traffic. His label, Dream Sequence Records, is working on assembling a roster and already has reached some &lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/dream-sequence-records/dowrong-shooters-prod-eric"&gt;talent&lt;/a&gt;. Jimmy Johnson and Eric Dingus should definitely be on your radar.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://333vinyl.us/if-we-hung-out-002/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">373b181c-e2eb-45b9-b749-87e48f0e6088</guid><category>articles</category><category>if we hung out</category><dc:creator>Mason Lynaugh</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Saddest//The Baddest: How To Be an Angsty Teen Girl 101: Summer Edition</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I'm Sophie from Whidbey Island in Washington State and I like to pretend I know what's cool. My music taste is pretty broad so I won't go into detail, but I will say I like Dave Matthews Band in a very un-ironic way. Here's what to listen to while smoking, painting nails, and driving home at 5 AM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: The War On Drugs  
Song: Red Eyes  
Album: Lost In The Dream  
Label: Secretly Canadian  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Red Eyes is the breakout song from what I might call one of the best albums of the year so far from Philadelphia’s The War On Drugs. Solely written by vocalist Adam Grandciel after a heartbreak, Lost In the Dream is expansive, lofty and filled with desire and melancholic beauty. Red Eyes is reminiscent of Springsteen craftsmanship: passion fueled vocal bursts and shouts, jangling piano chords, grinding crescendo leading to the chorus. The song signifies the end of a relationship, but it remains resiliently optimistic and almost elated. “I can see it in the darkness coming my way... Well we’re here” concludes Grandciel, the relationship at it’s close, as the song triumphantly rings out into the night; the soundtrack to a drive through the desert of self discovery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: The Radio Dept.  
Song: Heaven’s On Fire  
Album: Clinging To A Scheme  
Label: Labrador  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Swedish electro-pop trio’s most popular release is their most unusual record, and probably their most satirical. The track opens with a segment from Sonic Youth frontman Thurston Moore, who so boldly decries pop culture, capitalism, and even calls the youth to action to destroy this “bogus” society. And yet, through Moore’s last statements can be heard the openings of The Radio Dept.’s bubbling, frothy pink pop song almost mockingly piercing with their sweetness the sentiments of the political statement. It is the bands one and only take on a modern pop anthem, complete with the line “One look at you, and heaven’s on fire” breathed out into the waves and jingles of the track; a playful love song contrasted only by the opening statements. This song is summer in the the most innocent and quintessential means possible, yet the irony of singer Johan Ducanson’s counter phrase “One look at you, and hell’s on fire” and Thurston Moore’s opening interview leave the foaming keyboard barbed with hilarity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: Mac DeMarco  
Song: Ode To Viceroy  
Album: 2  
Label: Captured Tracks  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mac DeMarco is your typical stoner/slacker friend. Plaid shirt, scruffy smirk on his wide mouthed smile, and the inability to actually like anything in his life without a hint of sarcasm. However, this love song to DeMarco’s smoke of choice is the most un-ironic sentimentality you will hear from him. “Oh honey, I’ll smoke you ’til I’m dying” sighs DeMarco, as he coos over his beloved destruction, as his guitar soars sharply into the suburban night, or at the corner store “already running dry” or as the evening starts to dim the sky. DeMarco swears eternal faithfulness as he tenderly strums out his promises over the drums, never faltering, just like his love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: Lana Del Rey  
Song: Sad Girl  
Album: Ultraviolence  
Label: Polydor, Interscope  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ah, yes. No reference to teenage angst would be complete without a little Lana. Really, the entirety of Del Rey’s Ultraviolence could be on this list. The album is really not too different from 2012’s Born To Die, and although the hip hop influences from her earlier work are replaced with Dan Auberbach’s (The Black Keys) spaced out guitar solos and jazz effects, Del Rey still is heartbroken, struggling to achieve the irresistible American Dream, and setting out to prove once again that she’s not like “the other girls”. And although these themes are getting quite annoying, every single track on the album is stunning. But Sad Girl is Del Rey’s theme, filled to the top with rage repressed into beautiful longing, lovers who cannot be loved, floating vocals, and all the cinematic accompaniment that can be met with Del Rey’s whining “I’m a sad girl, a bad girl”. She’ll go to her grave defending her man even though his “bonnie on the side” makes her a sad, sad girl, and you just wouldn’t understand. Yet millions of pimpled faced adolescents who haven’t even moved out of the house still croon her ballads. This is perfection.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://333vinyl.us/the-saddestthe-baddest-how-to-be-an-angsty-teen-girl-101-summer-edition/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">65cf793c-a58e-4d9e-9982-818c66b14dcd</guid><category>articles</category><category>the saddest the baddest</category><dc:creator>Sophie Frank</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2014 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>If We Hung Out [001]</title><description>&lt;p&gt;My name is Mason Lynaugh and I will occasionally be contributing to 333vinyl. My musical tastes include Ben’s, but are more concerned with the most recent developments in hip hop - whether it be drill, coastal, trap, or slip-hop - so I will focus mainly on what has been blaring through my speakers on its path to being overplayed. I’m planning on doing periodical entries under the terrible title “if we hung out” because “songs I would make you listen to if we hung out” was a bit worse, and the people who do hang out with me would attest to its accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="more"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://333vinyl.us/content/images/2014/11/kanye.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r4NTDoPQ4mU"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kanye West - All Day (Remake)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: A triumphant victory for the lovely people over at KTT (or &lt;a href="http://333vinyl.us/ktt.jpg"&gt;KanyeToThe&lt;/a&gt;, a forum I endearingly refer to as the 4chan of hip hop) came the day in which someone announced they had a leak of the impending single from Kanye’s untitled seventh solo album. Ironically, this “leak” with the sound quality of something recorded on a graphing calculator triggered an infuriated Kanye to retreat back to Mexico and re-record for an album already rumored to be complete. Nonetheless, since I am part of that seeming minority that doesn’t mind Kanye’s rants, debauchery, or wife, and enjoys his music, I love this remake. Despite being full of mumbling, filler freestyle, unfinished lines, and of shoebox audio quality, it still bumps in the whip, dog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://333vinyl.us/content/images/2014/11/ilm.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HRQyg8RHvIQ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I LOVE MAKONNEN - I Don’t Sell Molly No More&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: ILM has recently received an unprecedented amount of attention for a singer who wails over beats churned out by ATL’s trap oligarchy while &lt;a href="http://www.foxylounge.com/IMG/jpg/i_love_makonnen_tumblr_mcxyf4addm1qlcgcbo1_500-2.jpg"&gt;undeniably resembling a plush toy in appearance&lt;/a&gt;. This is result of current king of rap Drake remixing his fantastic song &lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/octobersveryown/makonnen-ft-drake-tuesday"&gt;“Club Going Up On A Tuesday”&lt;/a&gt;.  “I Don’t Sell” is a grimy gem amongst ballads about mutual infidelity from his &lt;a href="http://www.hotnewhiphop.com/ilovemakonnen-i-love-makonnen-ep-new-mixtape.114225.html"&gt;self-titled EP&lt;/a&gt;, and is one of those songs that people “listen to as a joke” but show definite signs of enjoyment when it is played (think &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JxLS-cpgbe0"&gt;“Dolce and Gabanna”&lt;/a&gt;). I personally love ILM and look forward to his growth as an artist now that he has garnered some limelight a la &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OmHW9IzZYzU"&gt;Migos&lt;/a&gt;. No, I don’t care that you think he sounds like &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iq_d8VSM0nw"&gt;IceJJFish&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://333vinyl.us/content/images/2014/11/rustie.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_mO2VcJAkOw"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rustie - Attak (feat. Danny Brown)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: This is one of those songs that you may have already burnt out on if you’re a self-identifying “hip hop head”, into the contemporary EDM scene, or someone who lurks on Soundcloud. “Attak” marks the fourth collaboration between the two, and I see it as rivaling the incredible &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=22eSJgqxnX4"&gt;“Side B (Dope Song)"&lt;/a&gt; in quality. If you like Danny Brown, Rustie, Electronic music, and/or rap (that should be most everyone), this might tickle your pickle a little. Definitely a party starter up there with the Young Thug cut &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=34LyiriE6eo"&gt;“Old English”&lt;/a&gt; (also a must-listen).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://333vinyl.us/content/images/2014/11/mustard.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.howflyhiphop.com/2014/08/11/dj-mustard-face-down-download-mp3-lil-wayne-big-sean/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Face down (feat. Lil Wayne, Lil Boosie, Big Sean, YG)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Say what you will about DJ Mustard, I stand by my position that he has carved a ubiquitous sound and is deserving of all success. Some may get annoyed by the “aye aye aye” and the way that he uses the same sample kit across his entire discography, but those sounds have some parasitic quality that will infect its way to the top 40. “Face Down” comes from his rudimentary debut album 10 Summers, yet is anything but. It’s a classic love story - “she like her ass tooted up and her face down” with yet another verse from a Lil Wayne who is making admirable progress in &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VmddPo_c2oE"&gt;proving he’s still got it&lt;/a&gt;. However, the real standout here is Big Sean:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Oh my God, I’m in love with a porn star  
I’m in love with a foreign car, they both topless  
I done tricked off a gold Rolle wrist watch  
Man, I’m tired of dealing with these h--- but my d--- not  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://333vinyl.us/content/images/2014/11/mensa.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5jUGAVUwhRU"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Down On My Luck - Vic Mensa&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: By this point everyone knows Disclosure from &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=93ASUImTedo"&gt;“Latch”&lt;/a&gt;, but this Disclosure-produced song hasn’t gotten the love it deserves. I have trouble determining whether it’s alliance lies with EDM or rap, but those familiar with Vic Mensa know how his catalog dabbles in expansive &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZLp7M5SMBkQ"&gt;sonic&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gbcyfRztHmw"&gt;palettes&lt;/a&gt;. “Down On My Luck” is coupled with a clever Groundhog Day-inspired music video that serves as the cherry on top of one of my favorite jams for late drives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://333vinyl.us/content/images/2014/11/trae.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=D2IfOEp5iyE"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trae Tha Truth - Try Me (feat. Young Thug)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: I think Young Thug is the most interesting rapper making noise right now, and he is my second favorite rapper (behind Drake). He’s doing things that are just weird, and reaching commercial success &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5-0kZ_jeIHI"&gt;where other oddballs like Lil B couldn’t&lt;/a&gt;. His charisma and shrill, drawling flow permeate through a song until he owns it &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=etfIdtm-OC8"&gt;whether he is “featured” or not&lt;/a&gt;. Case in point, “Try Me” shows Young Thug partnering with the typically forgettable H-town hero to craft a contender for banger of the year.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://333vinyl.us/if-we-hung-out-001/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6c32bcae-6482-42ce-9515-845d6891fe8c</guid><category>articles</category><category>if we hung out</category><dc:creator>Mason Lynaugh</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2014 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>What I've Been Listening To [001]</title><description>&lt;p&gt;This week I finally went through a large portion of all the albums on my "to-listen" list. These are the ones I'm currently enjoying. Interestingly enough, seven of the nine albums are debuts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://333vinyl.us/content/images/2014/11/collage.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beach House - &lt;em&gt;Bloom&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: This is a great album that took me a few listens to get in to. It's not groundbreaking, but it's incredible high-quality and accessible dream pop. Good for sunrises, sunsets, and dusk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DIIV - &lt;em&gt;Oshin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Maybe the best way to describe this album is a rainy day at the beach. Great dreamy jam sound, reminiscient of Real Estate. "Doused" is a standout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Jesus and Mary Chain - &lt;em&gt;Psychocandy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Slacker shoegaze, or shoegaze before there was shoegaze. The JAMC's noisy guitars and airy vocals paved the way for My Bloody Valentine just three years later. And they didn't care. This is some of the catchiest and most indifferent noise you can get.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joy Division - &lt;em&gt;Unknown Pleasures&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: One of the best post-punk albums. Ian Curtis' baritone matches perfectly with the themes of isolation prevalent in his lyrics. The guitar and bass propell the songs through they airy abyss created by the drums. I'm going to listen to the follow-up &lt;em&gt;Closer&lt;/em&gt; soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Metric - &lt;em&gt;Old World Underground, Where Are You Now?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Metric's debut album. It sounds a lot different from their later work, but it has a good punk vibe. Creates a unique nervous atmosphere. I think it's about robots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Rapture - &lt;em&gt;Echoes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: One of the first true dance-punk albums. The Rapture also experiment with modern indie rock. Highlights include the Strokes-esque title track and lead single "House of Jealous Lovers." Definitely check this out if you're into dance-punk or early 2000s garage rock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ride - &lt;em&gt;Nowhere&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: This album is possibly the best that shoegaze has to offer outside of My Bloody Valentine. Opener "Seagull" is iconic, and the other tracks that fill out the album's short 39-minute runtime are almost as good. More accessible than some of the other popular shoegaze albums.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sonic Youth - &lt;em&gt;Daydream Nation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: "Teen Age Riot" is a masterpiece, the best track on what most say is Sonic Youth's best work. The album perfectly balances noise and rock, creating a unique sound that new indie acts are still trying to emulate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sunny Day Real Estate - &lt;em&gt;Diary&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: A definitive emo album. Not to be confused with A Sunny Day In Glasgow. Great guitar and vocal work. If you like "In Circles," you'll like the album. Perfect for warm summer night listening.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://333vinyl.us/what-ive-been-listening-to-001/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">b870f17d-3216-479f-b95f-00bb67cdcabc</guid><category>articles</category><category>what I've been listening to</category><dc:creator>Ben Bailey</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2014 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>