<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Sophie Frank - 333vinyl</title><description>The name of this site is 333vinyl. That's what it's about.</description><link>http://333vinyl.us/</link><generator>Ghost 0.5</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 21:47:26 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://333vinyl.us/author/sophiefrank/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>The Saddest//The Baddest: How To Be an Angsty Teen Girl 101: Winter Edition</title><description>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: Hundred Waters  
Song: Murmurs  
Album: The Moon Rang Like A Bell  
Label: OWSLA  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From one of the most intimate and subtlety enchanting albums of the year comes “Murmurs,” in my opinion, the standout track from &lt;em&gt;The Moon Rang Like A Bell&lt;/em&gt;. In yet another song that catapults you into the cosmos, Hundred Waters’ Nicole Miglis immerses you in her realities, setting you on the journey that is the whole record itself. Besides the piano, which guides you into Miglis’ &lt;code&gt;I wish you could see what I see&lt;/code&gt;, all these colliding sounds are so new, as are all these softly intimate layers to the vocals. The song is almost like entering a void of crashing comets and soaring planets, but all the while remaining so very December cold and bright. Skrillex signed Hundred Waters to his label with only one LP under their belt, on which they have expanded to their limits, filling in their reputation as the most willowy, whispery indie group of the year, and “Murmurs” is no exception. It is breathed into your ears, enters your soul, and like the video for the track so expertly depicts, almost prepares and repairs your being for a Winter season full of joy and sorrow; an embrace so close that you can feel the click of the tongue on the last &lt;code&gt;Silly silly silly me // I used to use to see // Now our holy holy light // Is blowing out&lt;/code&gt;. This almost Christmas-like hymn is that holy, holy light in the darkness of the chill. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: The Flavr Blue  
Song: No Remedy  
Album: Bright Vices  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a big supporter of fellow Seattle local Hollis Wong-Wear, co-writer of Macklemore’s White Walls and The Flavr Blue lead, so I might be a bit biased in choosing this for a track to listen to during the holiday season, that is, if you’re like me and you’d rather do anything than socialize. My winter self is especially bitter and somber, and screw you, I’m not depressed (Yeah, Dad)! I first heard The Flavr Blue’s FXF, which was the soundtrack to which me and a friend as we ended up lost in south Seattle and angry as hell at each other (long story), but 2013’s &lt;em&gt;Bright Vices&lt;/em&gt; strays away from their debut &lt;em&gt;Pisces&lt;/em&gt;’ reckless party fight anthems, and leads more to the route of rowdy synth-pop. Add the blend of Hollis’ lovely, twinkling champagne vocals that contrast the defiant chorus of &lt;code&gt;there's no remedy for the ways that i've changed // so i've nothing to lose walking into the flame&lt;/code&gt;, to floating, trance-like hooks and this song feels like a blustery, starry night. The entirety of the futuristic &lt;em&gt;Bright Vices&lt;/em&gt; is like being trapped in a cold, and beautiful space castle, but relatable enough that I used to sing along to these all these tracks in high school. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: Eskmo  
Song: Cloudlight  
Album: Eskmo  
Label: Ninja Tune  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brendan ‘Eskmo’ Angelides’ “Cloudlight” is more of a compilation of sounds than a song. It still fits with our chilly and aerial theme, although Angelides’ Moby-esque vocals, sparse, low and groveling, add to the moody and black depths of the track. The beats shuffle and whirl by the traveling listener, “floating and floating and floating in light” on a tour of the dark heavens, and it almost makes you dizzy. Lyrics are least important in this song; it’s more about the feelings of Angelides’ voice. The rough rawness of his tone pushes forward the zooms and zips of the infrequent synths. Listen to the rest of the album, and the sentiments continue forward hard-pressed, and grittier than ever. “Anger” is the word that comes to mind with “Got More,” the second track on Eskmo, maybe even “frustration”, but a frustration created with such intrigue and harsh, emphasized beats, accented by the sparsity of the vocals which are only necessary to give focus to the music. I won’t deny that “Cloudlight" lacks the holiday spirituality of “Murmurs,” but what it lacks in beauty, it makes up for in a deep and wintery enigma, punctuated by a reflectiveness that is most characteristic of late December, and waiting for the pending year to unfold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: Wye Oak  
Song: Civilian  
Album: Civilian  
Label: Merge  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saving the most humbled and grounded tunes for last, here is “Civilian,” by 21st-Century folk-rock duo Wye Oak. This song was featured in the 2012 film Safety Not Guaranteed, and as the characters booze their way through bumper cars and ferris wheels and go-karts, I fell in love with the sweet crescendos of Jenn Wasner’s lamentation on emotional weights coming crashing down upon an innocent bystander. Here we descend from our lofty, spacey anthems and enter earthly realities with a shock like a cold and crystal knife piercing the starry skies we’ve established with the previous floating and fanciful tracks. “Civilian”: partners become strangers; witnesses to a relationship overtaken by painful, heavy histories, the most honest of the narratives on our playlist. And now comes the explosive solo, reminiscent of Neil Young who leaves you sad and wanting to take a ride on a dark highway leading West. “Civilian” is chilly as it is arresting and pure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s to a cheerful winter season to soothe the cold and sad of heart. &lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://333vinyl.us/the-saddestthe-baddest-how-to-be-an-angsty-teen-girl-101-winter-edition/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">4aa42d5f-7744-4644-acc9-e421e359cc93</guid><dc:creator>Sophie Frank</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2014 23:53:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Saddest//The Baddest: How To Be an Angsty Teen Girl 101: Fall Edition</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I'm Sophie from Whidbey Island in Washington State and I like to pretend I know what's cool. My music taste is pretty broad so I won't go into detail, but I will say I like Dave Matthews Band in a very un-ironic way. Here's what to listen to while smoking, painting nails, and driving home at 5 AM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="more"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: Autre Ne Veut  
Song: Counting  
Album: Anxiety  
Label: Mexican Summer  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Counting," by Brooklyn producer Arthur Ashin (his name only revealed to fans recently, as to protect his identity during his studies in psychology for his masters degree), easily stands out as the most powerful track off of Autre Ne Veut’s February 2013 album Anxiety. Ashin’s delicate falsetto sets him apart from the sea of “bedroom R&amp;amp;B” producers, as well as his use of honking horn section squeaks and heavy groans that make up the underlying beat of "Counting"; so deep they feel almost pelvic. "Counting" is about ends—in particular, the death of Ashin’s grandmother. The falsetto cries out that &lt;code&gt;I’m counting on the idea that you’ll stay alive&lt;/code&gt; and now you understand the pain behind the lyrics, as well as the catharsis behind the anguish turned into soaring vocals and electronic trills. &lt;code&gt;This is not your time to make it out&lt;/code&gt; screams Ashin, imploring vitality to continue in this relationship, in this life, in this season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: Dum Dum Girls  
Song: There Is A Light That Never Goes Out  
Album: He Gets Me High EP  
Label: Sub Pop  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will refrain from claiming to like this cover of The Smiths' joyful lamentation better than the original, but it definitely comes close. Leading lady Kristen “Dee Dee” Gundred's voice is expansive and elastic. The solid strumming of the guitars are unbound and grinding. Gundred’s cover is almost more emotional than the never-outdone Morrissey. I can sense a bit of anger within her soft growl, but when it’s time for the chorus, the famous &lt;code&gt;And if a ten ton truck kills the both of us // to die by your side well the pleasure, the privilege is mine&lt;/code&gt;, the sentiment is soft and lovely, and infuses the melody with the utmost beauty. The guitars concede to the poetry of the song itself and to the vocals of the Dum Dum Girls, which have been uttered with a quite angelic element. The juxtaposition of these sweet female voices with Morrissey's raw songwriting makes this my song choice for my MP3 player whilst passing my college crush on the way across the quad as a way to feel powerful again under their gaze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: Ghost Loft  
Song: Seconds  
Album: Seconds  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Be there in seconds flat // Just tell me where you at// Everywhere you want to go// I’ve been there before// That means he don't need to know&lt;/code&gt; These are the opening lines of "Seconds," by Danny Choi, AKA LA producer Ghost Loft, who has created the ultimate track of nighttime secrecy. The tune itself is straightforward, but it seems to float into the night before the beat comes in. It is steady, and not quite sure of itself, but it evokes the feeling of urban anxiety; essentially fearful and extremely tentative. But the song feels like a journey, possibly to the doorstep of a lover. "Seconds" is dark, yet comforting with the presence of the quiet voice of track, who appeals to the delicacy and urgency of the actions made in the dead of the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: J. Tillman  
Song: Earthly Bodies  
Album: Year in the Kingdom  
Label: Western Vinyl  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could tell you about how I feel about fall: the severing of ties, the loss, the renewal, the journey into the darkness in order to grow and evolve… but I’m sure you’ve discovered what autumn means for yourself, or have read about it in some article about re-organizing your life in time for winter. Anyway, I first heard "Earthly Bodies" in an airport bathroom while taking my significant other to his flight back to England. Knowing I would not see him for a long time I was clearly a mess. I was wiping my eyes in the mirror and heard &lt;code&gt;Let me lay across your crescent spine // Press my belly to the mountainside&lt;/code&gt;. I conjured up the road trip I had just taken with my love: the lazy day by the river in the middle of the still-snow-capped mountains amid the shade of green only seen in the Northwest. I got home a few hours later and thought about starting over at college soon and about the autumn of the Northeast. "Earthly Bodies" played as I fell asleep dreaming about the cold weather and healing my hurting heart. Four months later, as I sit in my dorm room that over looks the burgundy-colored quad, J. Tillman’s ballad to transformation, love lost and found in the pleasure of connections to people and nature, and finding comfort within another person still plays. The fall season continues to change me through music, walks in the forest in the glory of Massachusetts, and nostalgia of summer memories with my boyfriend. &lt;code&gt;Baby, lay your head where we begin and end&lt;/code&gt; Tillman sings, asking us through his soft-spoken, wondering-at-the-world poetry that we remember fall is both the end and the start of the cycle of holding on and letting go.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://333vinyl.us/the-saddestthe-baddest-how-to-be-an-angsty-teen-girl-101-fall-edition/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">62f9d3ef-16f1-4fc8-9e22-8b1e80461c38</guid><category>articles</category><category>the saddest the baddest</category><dc:creator>Sophie Frank</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2014 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Saddest//The Baddest: How To Be an Angsty Teen Girl 101: Summer Edition</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I'm Sophie from Whidbey Island in Washington State and I like to pretend I know what's cool. My music taste is pretty broad so I won't go into detail, but I will say I like Dave Matthews Band in a very un-ironic way. Here's what to listen to while smoking, painting nails, and driving home at 5 AM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: The War On Drugs  
Song: Red Eyes  
Album: Lost In The Dream  
Label: Secretly Canadian  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Red Eyes is the breakout song from what I might call one of the best albums of the year so far from Philadelphia’s The War On Drugs. Solely written by vocalist Adam Grandciel after a heartbreak, Lost In the Dream is expansive, lofty and filled with desire and melancholic beauty. Red Eyes is reminiscent of Springsteen craftsmanship: passion fueled vocal bursts and shouts, jangling piano chords, grinding crescendo leading to the chorus. The song signifies the end of a relationship, but it remains resiliently optimistic and almost elated. “I can see it in the darkness coming my way... Well we’re here” concludes Grandciel, the relationship at it’s close, as the song triumphantly rings out into the night; the soundtrack to a drive through the desert of self discovery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: The Radio Dept.  
Song: Heaven’s On Fire  
Album: Clinging To A Scheme  
Label: Labrador  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Swedish electro-pop trio’s most popular release is their most unusual record, and probably their most satirical. The track opens with a segment from Sonic Youth frontman Thurston Moore, who so boldly decries pop culture, capitalism, and even calls the youth to action to destroy this “bogus” society. And yet, through Moore’s last statements can be heard the openings of The Radio Dept.’s bubbling, frothy pink pop song almost mockingly piercing with their sweetness the sentiments of the political statement. It is the bands one and only take on a modern pop anthem, complete with the line “One look at you, and heaven’s on fire” breathed out into the waves and jingles of the track; a playful love song contrasted only by the opening statements. This song is summer in the the most innocent and quintessential means possible, yet the irony of singer Johan Ducanson’s counter phrase “One look at you, and hell’s on fire” and Thurston Moore’s opening interview leave the foaming keyboard barbed with hilarity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: Mac DeMarco  
Song: Ode To Viceroy  
Album: 2  
Label: Captured Tracks  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mac DeMarco is your typical stoner/slacker friend. Plaid shirt, scruffy smirk on his wide mouthed smile, and the inability to actually like anything in his life without a hint of sarcasm. However, this love song to DeMarco’s smoke of choice is the most un-ironic sentimentality you will hear from him. “Oh honey, I’ll smoke you ’til I’m dying” sighs DeMarco, as he coos over his beloved destruction, as his guitar soars sharply into the suburban night, or at the corner store “already running dry” or as the evening starts to dim the sky. DeMarco swears eternal faithfulness as he tenderly strums out his promises over the drums, never faltering, just like his love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: Lana Del Rey  
Song: Sad Girl  
Album: Ultraviolence  
Label: Polydor, Interscope  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ah, yes. No reference to teenage angst would be complete without a little Lana. Really, the entirety of Del Rey’s Ultraviolence could be on this list. The album is really not too different from 2012’s Born To Die, and although the hip hop influences from her earlier work are replaced with Dan Auberbach’s (The Black Keys) spaced out guitar solos and jazz effects, Del Rey still is heartbroken, struggling to achieve the irresistible American Dream, and setting out to prove once again that she’s not like “the other girls”. And although these themes are getting quite annoying, every single track on the album is stunning. But Sad Girl is Del Rey’s theme, filled to the top with rage repressed into beautiful longing, lovers who cannot be loved, floating vocals, and all the cinematic accompaniment that can be met with Del Rey’s whining “I’m a sad girl, a bad girl”. She’ll go to her grave defending her man even though his “bonnie on the side” makes her a sad, sad girl, and you just wouldn’t understand. Yet millions of pimpled faced adolescents who haven’t even moved out of the house still croon her ballads. This is perfection.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://333vinyl.us/the-saddestthe-baddest-how-to-be-an-angsty-teen-girl-101-summer-edition/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">65cf793c-a58e-4d9e-9982-818c66b14dcd</guid><category>articles</category><category>the saddest the baddest</category><dc:creator>Sophie Frank</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2014 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>