<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Sara Turner - 333vinyl</title><description>The name of this site is 333vinyl. That's what it's about.</description><link>http://333vinyl.us/</link><generator>Ghost 0.5</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 21:47:26 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://333vinyl.us/author/saraturner/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>Eclectic Essentials [001]</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Hi, I’m Sara and I will be contributing to 333vinyl. My taste includes the foundation of indie rock central to the site in addition to special detail to female vocalists and experimental alternative rock. In the interest of saving everyone’s time, let me guide you, the reader, through four albums that I feel represent my basis and growth as a music fan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://333vinyl.us/content/images/2014/11/collage.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: Britney Spears  
Album: Blackout  
Released: 2007  
First listen: 2007  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do not think I am beginning our relationship on the wrong foot, dear reader. Truly, pop music was the first cement poured into my malleable ears, and it has stuck with me since. My previous music reviews have all been for contemporary pop albums, including Spears’ 2011 album &lt;em&gt;Femme Fatale&lt;/em&gt;. In addition, &lt;em&gt;Blackout&lt;/em&gt; taught me not to judge an album by its artist. Publicity for the album occurred during Spears’ highly publicized personal struggles, heavily affecting sales. This did not stop me from receiving a copy from my obsessed best friend, who told me to give her a chance. The first lesson that &lt;em&gt;Blackout&lt;/em&gt; taught me was to take risks when choosing what music to listen to and to shirk preconceptions and previous opinions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I’ve explained myself: Blackout is a good album. A damn good album, at that. You would think because the only single that truly took off was the controversial “Gimme More”, which was (and is) treated as a joke by the press, the entire album is brainless pop litter. But it’s truly the opposite: &lt;em&gt;Blackout&lt;/em&gt; is revolutionary electro-pop that showcases techniques later adopted and brought into the mainstream by other artists. Most notable is the dubstep-influenced breakdown in “Freakshow,” a full four years before another’s appearance in her record-breaking #1 “Hold It Against Me.” Spears is referred to as the Princess of Pop for a reason—she continually works with producers who break the boundaries and with whom she makes pop history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: Snow Patrol  
Album: Final Straw  
Released: 2003  
First listen: 2009  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, I was turned on to indie rock. My first introduction to the genre was Death Cab for Cutie’s “I Will Possess Your Heart,” which lead me to pursue like-minded artists. Both Death Cab and Snow Patrol had songs on in Wicker Park, a critically-panned film with an incredible motion picture soundtrack. It was there that I discovered pre-“Chasing Cars” Snow Patrol through “How to Be Dead,” a poignant introduction to the kinds of feelings that lead vocalist and songwriter Gary Lightbody evokes. &lt;em&gt;Final Straw&lt;/em&gt; was when I started to identify with lyrics and study the intricacies of them, which is a byproduct of my love for prose in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: Fiona Apple  
Album: Extraordinary Machine  
Released: 2005  
First listen: 2010  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before reaching for &lt;em&gt;Extraordinary Machine&lt;/em&gt;, I had listened to Apple’s previous two albums, having been working through her discography. What intrigued me most about &lt;em&gt;Extraordinary Machine&lt;/em&gt; is that two versions of it exist—a leaked bootleg produced exclusively by Jon Brion and sprinkled with strings, and the official release with completely different arrangements on all but two songs and the added “Parting Gift.” The politics behind the music industry interest me and Machine is a classic representation of the label screwing the artist. In addition, demo and bootleg recordings fascinate me on a basic level: that which we were never supposed to hear has been taken from the vaults so that we may appreciate its existence. Unreleased works thrown into the mainstream are like poetry in a way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: OK Go  
Album: Of the Blue Colour of the Sky  
Released: 2010  
First listen: 2010  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK Go is my favorite band.  It has taken me seven years of exploring music to be able to find a band that represents all that I love about music, and in 2009 I finally found them. Mostly famous for their DIY, one-take music videos, OK Go are also masters of something beautiful: doing whatever the hell they want. After reaching mainstream success with “Here It Goes Again” and much tension, they left their major label and formed their own. Blue Colour is their first independent release and exemplifies their own eclectic taste—funky psychedelics present in “In the Glass” contrast the acoustic beauty of “Last Leaf.” OK Go writes songs about regret, desire, perseverance, and, put succinctly, the essence of life. OK Go represents all that I love about music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all, I look forward to exploring my eclectic music taste with 333vinyl. It truly runs the gamut from &lt;code&gt;I struggle for the words and then give up / My head’s up with the birds on the T-hut&lt;/code&gt; (“Spitting Games” – Snow Patrol) to &lt;code&gt;If I got on top, you're gonna lose your mind&lt;/code&gt; ("Get Naked [I Got a Plan]" – Britney Spears). Follow me on &lt;a href="http://www.last.fm/user/maymayyy"&gt;Last.fm&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.twitter.com/saatuna"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://333vinyl.us/eclectic-essentials-001/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">ac827fda-f339-4508-875f-24d927adc181</guid><category>articles</category><category>eclectic essentials</category><dc:creator>Sara Turner</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2014 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Rilo Kiley - The Execution of All Things</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://333vinyl.us/content/images/2014/11/rilo_kiley-the_execution_of_all_things.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi, I’m Sara and I will be contributing to 333vinyl. My taste includes the foundation of indie rock central to the site in addition to special detail to female vocalists and experimental alternative rock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depression is a strange thing. It influences your capacity to create, so creative people tend to go through periods of inactivity. With its terror comes a common ground that all people with depression can fall back upon. This foundation is exemplified in Rilo Kiley’s sophomore album, &lt;em&gt;The Execution of All Things&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having loss and regret at the forefront of this album made it easy to connect to during one of my own episodes. The opening track, “The Good That Won’t Come Out”, tugs on the bottom of your coat until you’re forced to listen to what it has to say. Right away, vocalist Jenny Lewis attempts to make a connection with the listener: “let’s get together and talk about the modern age.” A desire to stray from stagnation makes its appearance through the album, along with Lewis and co-vocalist Blake Sennett’s personal experiences with depression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“You say I choose sadness, that it never once has chosen me. Maybe you’re right.” (“The Good That Won’t Come Out”)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Musically, &lt;em&gt;The Execution of All Things&lt;/em&gt; is of the standard indie pop rock fare that made its rounds in the early 2000s. It is less inspired by country rock compared to their previous efforts, more so matching the Omaha Sound referenced in the title track “The Execution of All Things”. After all, the record was released off of Saddle Creek Records, founded by Bright Eyes’ frontman Conor Oberst. However, &lt;em&gt;The Execution of All Things&lt;/em&gt; does continue down the established path of its predecessor by incorporating electronic sounds—not quite the MIDI-like interludes of &lt;em&gt;Take Offs and Landings&lt;/em&gt;, but like the introduction to the title track, an anticipatory build to the reflective prose within. Its frank delivery of lyrics is what makes the album truly unique and what increased their recognition in the scene with their next album, &lt;em&gt;More Adventurous&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, similar to the “Variations on a Theme” interludes from their first album, pieces of a song appear throughout the album after “So Long”, “My Slumbering Heart”, and “Spectacular Views”. This song delivered in three parts is named by its last lyric, “And That’s How I Choose to Remember It”. The song is an exposition on the divorce of Lewis’ parents and her childhood that perfectly strings together the album’s motifs and adds to its overall cohesiveness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lewis was undoubtedly the face of the band (which broke up in 2011); however, there are still two tracks with vocals by Sennett on the album. The stronger of the two is “Three Hopeful Thoughts”, a hard rocking song about the removal of someone from one’s life. There are many goodbyes on this album: to parents, to lovers, to parts of one’s self. The kind of goodbye explored on this song is one that the author is in control of and actively wants, a contrast to the others present. This gives the song and subsequently the album a different kind of hope: a hope that acknowledges the pain of the past but also focuses on the opportunities of the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stand-out track on an album filled with poignant insights is also its biggest hit, “A Better Son/Daughter”. It turns the themes of the album to max volume at the most important moment, guiding the listener through the portion of a depressive episode where one realizes they will have to fight and make it through the fog, reminding them that the good may be gone for now but it can still come out of them. &lt;em&gt;The Execution of All Things&lt;/em&gt; is an essential part of Rilo Kiley’s catalog and a quintessential indie-rock representation of grief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Artist: Rilo Kiley  
Album: The Execution of All Things  
Score: 4.5  
Label: Saddle Creek  
Release: 2002/10/01  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description><link>http://333vinyl.us/rilo-kiley-the-execution-of-all-things/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">89630df5-40ca-4f17-905f-b1bc1552194e</guid><category>reviews</category><dc:creator>Sara Turner</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2014 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>